皓瀚霏凡 压制
-=圣城家园 CnSCG 荣誉出品=-
HD.CnSCG.Com
皓瀚霏凡 特效字幕制作
-=圣城家园 CnSCG 荣誉出品=-
HD.CnSCG.Com
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
协调: 兜兜  校对: 桃茜茜 柚子茶 影子
翻译: 故故 小U回来了 胖蛋屎妞 唐醋于 D调的张扬 荧惑。zhuceba 小海涛 小FA
我们曾是一个和平的智能机械体种族
We were once a peaceful race of intelligent mechanical beings.
接着 战争爆发了
But then came the war.
战争的双方 一方是为自由而战的汽车人们
Between the autobots who fought for freedom,
另一方是妄想专政的霸天虎们
and the decepticons in draft of tyranny.
敌众我寡 数量悬殊
Over matched, and out numbered.
我们几乎战败
Our defeat was all but certain.
但是在战争的最后几天里
But in the wars final days,
一艘汽车人的飞船逃离了战场
one autobot ship escaped the battle.
它载着一船能够扭转战局
It was carrying a secret cargo,
改变我们星球命运的神秘物品
which would have changed our planets fate.
这是一次绝地任务
A desperate mission.
这是我们最后的希望
Our final hope.
而这个希望 最后破灭了
A hope, that vanished.
国家射电天文台 新墨西哥州 1961年
往那边移动
Move it over there.
继续移动 再往下一点
Move it over there, one more down there.
发生什么了?
Whatcha got?
检测到撞击
Impact detected.
已确认撞击
We have impact confirmed.
联系政府方面
Contacted.
美国宇航局指挥部 弗吉尼亚州兰利市
- 格林威治时间22点50分  - 什么?
- 22:50 GMT.  - What?
给我接通安全发展部的电话
Give me SEC-DEV on the phone right away.
紧急通知
发现外太空活动轨迹
侦测月球发生撞击
于格林威治时间22:50接触地外智慧
五角大楼 美国国防部
麦克纳马拉先生 总统先生在等你
Mr. McNamara, the President is expecting you.
- 把鲍比叫过来  - 总统先生
- Get Bobby in here.  - Mr. President.
请求指示 高度机密
Definition, top secret.
我们刚刚检测到一个不明飞行物体撞击了月球
We believe a UFO has crashed into the moon.
而且我们认为苏联方面也正在关注此事
We think the Russians are on to it as well.
你告诉宇航局准备探索外太空
Well then you tell NASA to move heaven and earth.
我们必需登上月球
We need to get to the moon.
我们将启动一项载人航天计划
We're going to attempt a manned mission.
美国宇航局方面表示此计划将花费五年时间
NASA said it would take five years.
你们必须在苏联人之前上去
You get there before the Russians.
我认为我们应该尽全国之力
I believe that this nation should commit itself,
在这个年代末
to achieving the goal.
- 倒数十五秒  - 完成登月的目标
- Fifteen seconds.  - Before this decade is out,
把一位宇航员送到月球
of landing a man on the moon,
并且再安全地把他带回地球
and returning him safely to the earth.
点火程序启动
Ignition sequence starts
五 四 三 二 一
Five, four, three, two, one.
八年后 1969年7月16日
点火
And ignition.
升空了 火箭已发射升空
Lift off, we have a lift off.
已经过去一小时三十二分钟
Thirty two minutes past the hour.
距离阿波罗11号从三号发射塔升空
Lift off on Apollo 11, tower three.
阿波罗11号正借助着
Apollo 11 is on the way.
土星五号喷射的火焰 在太空中翱翔
Riding that pillar of flame from the Saturn five.
在二十五万英里外
Out there 250,000 miles away,
月球正等待着人类的第一次到达
where the moon is waiting for man's first arrival.
休斯顿 准备登陆 完毕
Houston you're a go for landing, over.
40英尺 向下移动2.5英尺 碰到些许灰尘
40 feet, down 2 1/2. Kicking up some dust.
30英尺 向下移动2.5英尺
Thirty feet, two and a half down. Faint shadow
向前移动4英尺 向右偏移一点
Four Forward. Drifting to the right a little.
20英尺 再向下移动0.5英尺
20 feet, down a half.
打开着陆灯
Contact light.
好的 关闭发动机
Okay, engine stop.
休斯顿 这里是静海基地 小鹰号着陆舱已经登陆
Houston, tranquility base here, The Eagle has landed.
我们都快紧张得快憋死了
You got a bunch of guys about to turn blue.
现在终于能喘口气了
We're breathing again.
今天 大约有4亿人正在观看今日的直播
Perhaps 400 million persons are watching this broadcast today,
共同见证人类史上最伟大的时刻
of the greatest event in our time.
也是将载入人类史册的最伟大的事件之一
And one of the great events of all recorded history.
我已经站在梯子的底部
I'm at the foot of the ladder.
我即将踏上月球的土地
I'm going to step on to land now.
这是我个人的一小步
That's one small step for man,
却是人类的一大步
one giant leap for mankind.
- 一切顺利吗?  - 是的
- Are we good?  - Yes sir.
转到1092非正式频道...
An official time on the first step 1092...
我们这边有些信号干扰
Eagle we're getting a signal interference.
小鹰号 听得到吗?
Do you copy?
刚刚得到证实 与阿波罗11号的联系暂时出现中断
We now have a confirmation. Loss of signal from Apollo 11.
现在阿波罗11号 正在月球的背面
The Apollo 11 is for the moment, on the far side of the moon.
尼尔 你们现在正在月球的暗面
Neil, you are dark on the rock.
开始执行任务
Mission is a go.
你们有21分钟时间
You have 21 minutes.
准备 开始计时 18分45秒
Please stand by, 3 minutes and 45 seconds and counting.
天呐
My god.
看上去像是某种巨型金属脸
It's some sort of giant metal face.
上帝啊
Jesus.
控制中心 我们已经进入了飞船
Control, we are inside the ship.
大面积受损
Extensive damage.
体积太大 无法面面俱到
Way to big to check the entire ship.
休斯顿 这里一片死气沉沉
Everything is dead in here, Houston.
没有丝毫生命迹象
No signs of life anywhere.
这里看上去一团糟
This thing is massive.
我们知道了
We copy.
你们的氧气还够七分钟
You got seven minutes on your oxygen.
宇宙当中 不是只有我们 对吧
We are not alone after all, are we.
是的 先生
No, sir.
并不是只有我们
We're not alone.
好了 开始吧总统先生
All right, go ahead Mr. President.
尼尔 巴兹 你们好
Hello, Neil, Buzz.
我在白宫的圆形办公室...
I'm talking to you by telephone...
...给你们打电话
...from the oval room at the White House.
这显然会是...
And this certainly has to...
...最具有历史意义的一次电话通话
...be the most historic telephone call ever made.
我们的骄傲之情 无以言表
I just can't tell you how proud we all are.
对于每位美国人来说 这将会是我们生命里 最骄傲的一天
For every American, this has to be the proudest day of our lives.
因为你们的壮举
Because of what you have done.
我们成功着陆
We have splashed down.
太空已经成为了人类世界的一部分
The heavens has become a part of man's world.
这是极其珍贵的一刻
For one priceless moment.
在人类所有的历史当中
In all of history of man.
全球的人类 都真心实意地
All the people on this earth are truly one.
为你们的壮举 而感到骄傲
Along with their pride in which you have done.
你们激励着我们 要加倍努力地
You've inspired us to redouble our efforts,
为这颗星球 带来和平与宁静
to bring peace and tranquility to Earth.
变形金刚
月黑之时
我的大英雄 该起来了
My hero, needs to wake up.
那是什么?
What is that?
这是你的新幸运兔
This is your new lucky bunny.
卡莉 这想法不错
Yeah, it's a beautiful thought, Carly.
但我觉得幸运的不是整个兔子
But I don't think it's the whole, uh, bunny that's lucky.
你看 只是这个部位
You see it's just this section here.
你看 只有兔子腿才是幸运的
You see it's just the rabbit's foot that's lucky.
好吧 只是个吉祥物罢了
All right, it's just a good luck charm.
嘿嘿 它可以帮你乐观一点
Hmm, help you think positive.
今天可是个重要的日子
Today's important.
来 快起来
Come on, get up.
- 戴上那条帅领带  - 好
- Hey, wear that nice tie.  - Yeah.
需要给你午饭钱吗?
You need any money for lunch?
不 不用你给我午饭钱
No, I don't need any money for lunch.
昨天的午饭钱还有剩
I have money from yesterday's lunch.
你很喜欢这样 是吧?
You love it, don't you.
我只是你的美国小帅哥玩偶
I'm just your American boy-toy.
一个恋人玩偶
I love boy-toy.
你知道 一个拯救过世界两次的人 却要卑躬屈膝地
You know how demoralizing it is to save the world twice,
去找工作 是有多恼人吗
to be groveling for a job.
他们不知道你拯救过世界 萨姆
They don't know you saved the world, Sam.
我是说 我知道 我相信你
I mean I do, I believe you.
要是人人都知道的话 我就能在华盛顿这儿找个工作了
Government knows, but he doesn't give me a job right here in D.C.
我是说我应该和汽车人一起工作
I mean I should be working with the autobots.
不然 就太不公平了
Otherwise, it's not fair.
别这样 他们已经帮你付了大学的学费
Come on, they paid for your college.
总统还给了你一个英雄勋章
The president gave you a hero medal.
伙计 谢谢你 干得好
Thank you, man. Great job.
而且我记得
And as I recall
那甚至不是你最风光的一天
that wasn't even the highlight of your day.
大使先生 这边请
Mr. Ambassador, here.
下一个是你们英国大使馆
British Embassy you're up next.
- 这其实不那么...  - 不 你不能戴着
- It's not really...  - No, you don't wear it.
- 即便我想也不能  - 收起来
- I couldn't even if I wanted to.  - Leave it there.
收到箱子里 好吧
Leave it in the box, right.
你把它放在这里 多好看的箱子啊
You keep it in there, what a gorgeous box.
哦 这是我的奖章
Oh yeah, my medal.
你知道谁颁发给我的吗?
You know who gave that to me?
谁?
Who?
- 美国总统  - 哦
- POTUS.  - Oh.
美利坚合众国总统
The President of the United States.
其实大家找工作都挺难的
Hey, it's hard for everybody to get a job.
我没时间了
I don't have time.
你瞧 我爸妈开始他们的房车环球之旅
You see, my parents are going to be here in a week.
下星期就要到这里了
From their road-trip party world tour.
到时候我老爸来这儿 知道我还没工作
My dad gets here, and I don't have a job.
他会抽我一顿 我得走了
He's gonna spank me you know. It's go time for me.
好吧 今天晚上我给你个工作
All right, tonight I'll give you a job.
给我准备一顿浪漫的晚餐...
Romance me with a nice dinner and, uh...
或者把那东西赶走
maybe you'll get that bonus.
- 真好看  - 给我出去
- Good looking.  - Get out of here.
等等 别 别 别 别 别
Wait, no, no, no, no, no.
哦 他好粗鲁啊
Oh, he's gross.
她倒是挺温柔的
She's good.
他们是流亡到这的
They've been stranded here,
总得有个人照顾他们 你懂得
somebody's got to watch out for them, you know.
昨天那个还躲到我内衣柜子里去了
Yesterday that one was in my underwear drawer.
好借口 从下面看身材也不错哦
Good reason, it looked real good too.
- 你打谁呢?  - 我只想要个平凡的男友
- What are you hitting, huh?  - I want a normal boyfriend.
这正是你爱我的原因 不是吗?
That's what you love about me, isn't it?
呵 这小抱怨鬼
Heh, what a cry baby.
我还没有说过这个字哦
You know I don't have the word yet.
等你能跟我平摊房租的时候 或许我们的感情能更进一步
Maybe a little bit closer when you can pay your half of the rent.
再见
Bye.
我淋雨淋得都快短路了
Frinking shorting my circuits out here.
太惨无人道了
It's inhumane, what it is.
让我们住在阳台的箱子里
Make us live in a box on a balcony.
还和一个畜生为邻
Right next to a beast.
- 正常一点  - 别说 好吧
- Like a common animal.  - Stop, okay.
你和你那怪异的朋友
You and your creepy psychic,
没有许可 不得进来
you can't be in here without permission.
谁的许可 那位金发小妞?
According to who, Miss blondy-blonde?
快走小狗狗
Get out little doggie.
你脑袋怎么了?
Yo brain's what's up?
没事
Doing good.
啊开枪了 我看过这段
Ah shoot, I'd seen this one.
这次斯波克(星际迷航中的角色)发疯了
It's the one where Spock goes nuts.
萨姆 我不知道该怎么和这个小妞共处
You know Sam, I don't know about moving in with this chick.
要是她像你的前任那样 把我们甩了怎么办?
Uh, what if she dumps us like the last girl?
她对我们多坏啊 不喜欢她
What she was mean, didn't like her.
我们哥几个得团结一致
Us guys got to stick together.
不 谁跟你一伙儿啊 你可是个政治难民
No, we're not family. You're a political refugee.
但是对我来说 我终于找到了真正欣赏我的人
And I have finally found someone who appreciates me for me.
那你告诉她我们不是你的宠物
Well you tell her that we're not your pets.
也不是你的玩具
And we're not your toys.
好不 我们是高级的智慧的的外星种族
All right, we're an advanced genius alien race,
只不过没地方住罢了
just looking for a home.
- 我们可以直接停在这  - 我觉得我们不应该停
- We could leave it right here.  - Didn't think we should stop.
得了 他们能怎么办 拖走?
Come on, what are they going to do, tow it?
儿子在哪?
Where is he?
萨米!
Sammy!
- 哦 别这样 这可不好笑 哈哈  - 嗨萨姆
- Oh, come on that's funny, ha, ha.  - Sam.
我很想念你们
I miss you guys so much.
那当然 怎么样?
Sure you did, what do you think?
- 挺不错  - 可爱极了
- Look at that.  - Cute.
- 上帝呀  - 别说了
- Gold.  - Stop it.
我们一直在这等你...
Wait until you see the end.
哦 我喜欢你这条小领带
Oh I love your little tie.
嘿 咱家媳妇儿在哪?
Hey, where's my girl?
- 咱家媳妇儿呢 我们漂亮的卡莉呢?  - 她去工作了 妈
- where's my beautiful Carly?  - She's at work, Ma.
- 她找到新工作了  - 好极了
- She's got a new job.  - Right.
我原以为你们要一周后才来这儿
I thought you were going to be here in a week.
11月21号 爸记得吗?
The 21st of the 11th, Dad remember?
- 这完全是...  - 我们快马加鞭赶过来的
- It's all the enthusiastic thing...  - ... A love job with flies.
哦 是不是我们耽误你什么事了?
Oh, are we keeping you from something?
比如 你的工作
Like say, your job.
时间差不多了
Well it's about time.
你让我们担心了
You had us worried.
其实 我是准备去面试
Uh, I have, uh, job interviews.
哦 那挺好
Oh, that's good.
- 那很糟  - 别说了
- That sucks.  - Stop it.
老爸 你不用这么悲观 你看
You don't have to be so negative dad, you know.
你现在在华盛顿 和你的儿子 你的家庭在一起
You're in DC, you're here with your son, your family.
这是个好时光
I mean it's good times.
除了你没有工作这事真让人郁闷
It sucks that you don't have a job.
- 还有很多美好的事情要去做 对吧?  - 是啊
- Good things to do here too, right?  - Yeah.
你看 图书馆 纪念碑 好吧
Right, museums and monuments, okay.
- 晚上我再来找你们  - 我还要去猎山羊
- I'll see you tonight.  - I'm bagging the gift.
萨姆 我觉得你去面试得穿条像样的裤子
Sam, I think for an interview you should wear real pants.
我觉得为了生活 你就得穿条像样的裤子
I think for life you should wear real pants.
哦 这... 大黄蜂呢?
Oh, wha... what happened to Bumble Bee?
他去执行任务了 这是我的备用车
He's off on his missions, I had to get this as a back-up.
哦 连你的车都有工作了啊?
Oh, your car has a job, huh?
它能变成啥?
What does it change into?
这辆车不能变形
It doesn't change into anything.
它是个收藏品 我从地摊上淘来的
It's a collectors' item, I got it for a steal.
这车慢慢开挺好的 相信我
It just needs some work, trust me.
哦 看着它感觉挺亲切的 让我想起大黄峰
Oh, I think it's darling. It reminds me a lot of Bumble Bee.
要是大黄峰也像它这么烂的话
If Bumble Bee were a sad piece of shit.
过来 我们载你一程
Come on we'll give you a ride.
自从我们到来之后
In the years since our arrival.
我们的新家 地球改变了许多
Our new home, Earth had seen much change.
超能量检测仪保卫着城市
Energon detectors guard its cities now.
远程防御系统守护着领空
Long range defense systems watch the skies.
中东 非法核站点
现在我们协助盟友
So now we assist our allies,
化解人类冲突
in solving human conflicts.
防止他们互相伤害
To prevent mankind from bringing harm to itself.
是国防部长的车
The Defense Minister's car.
趴下 不许动 老实呆着
On the ground. Better not move, and stay there.
我们组成秘密分队 在全球范围执行任务
We work in secret teams on various missions around the globe.
同时 我们也在寻找宿敌
And all the while, we search for signs,
卷土重来的蛛丝马迹
of our true enemies return.
我是沃斯霍德
I am Voshkod,
乌克兰能源部的法律顾问
General Council with Ukrainian Department of Energy.
政府将将会正式否认...
My government will officially deny...
...我们进行了此次对话
...that we're having this conversation.
我们在清理一所污染设施时有些新发现
At one of our decontamination facilities a discovery was made,
恐怕是外星人的痕迹
which I fear may be alien in nature.
这座核设施就是切尔诺贝利
The Facility's name is, Chernobyl.
沃斯霍德先生
Mr. Voshkod.
自86年至今 一直废弃着
Uninhabited since '86.
据说2万年内都不能住人
I hear it won't be livable again for another 20,000 years.
至少2万年 乌克兰原来是土地肥沃 真是场悲剧
At least. Ukraine was the most fertile land, it's a tragedy.
这边走
This way.
戴好面罩 我们只有一分钟的时间
Gear up, we have 60 minutes on the ground.
多留意周围辐射量
Watch your radiation levels.
沃斯霍德先生 你的面罩呢?
Mr. Voshkod, where's your protective gear?
你怎么不戴面罩?
Where's your protective gear?
不必了
It would not matter.
我已经是个等死的人了
For me it's only a matter of time.
穿过这校园
Through the school.
尤里会带你下去
Uri will take you below.
还有件事 上校 别说出去
And one other thing, Colonel, in private.
这儿进行过军事试...
There are some energy strength...
一会说吧
It can wait.
前进 都跟紧点
Keep moving, stay tight.
就这儿 到了 拿灯过来
Okay, right here. Bring up the light.
长官 看见了
Officer, we got a visual.
这儿有个东西 像是被金属条给困住了
We've found an object. Strapped in some kind of metal harness.
这是什么?
What's this?
嘿
Guys,
这上面怎么有苏联太空计划的标志？
Why does this thing have Soviet space program markings on it?
- 斯普特尼克号  - 存在超能量 长官
- Sputnik.  - Energon readings, sir.
很强烈
It's strong.
在我们底下
Below us.
来势迅猛
It's coming fast.
快跑 过去
Go there, go there.
快上去 快
Get to top, right now.
撤 快走!
Let's go, let's go!
快走 带上重武器
Let's go its an autobot.
快躲我身后
Stay behind me.
快走 走!
Move, move!
擎天柱!
Optimus!
撤!
Fall back!
从侧面攻击 侧面 快
Bring it flank, bring it flank come on.
准备重武器
Get the heavy weapons.
擎天柱
Optimus.
那他妈到底是什么?
What the hell was that thing?
那就是震荡波
That is Shockwave.
他要这个干吗?
Why was he after this?
不可能的
It's impossible.
这是一块引擎的零件
This is an engine part.
来自一艘失踪已久的汽车人飞船
From a long lost autobot ship.
合作愉快
Pleasure working with you.
去面试咯 真令人兴奋
Interviews. This is so exciting.
宝贝 要嚼口香糖吗?
Honey, do you want some gum?
你一紧张 口气就很重
Your breath gets really gnarly when you're nervous.
威特维奇先生
Mr. Whit... wickey.
不用找啦
Yep, the search is over.
我是惠特利先生
I'm Mr. Whitley.
- 还有别人吗?  - 没了
- Is any one else joining?  - No.
没了?
No?
- 想让我坐在那里吗? 我没关系  - 还是别了
- Want me to move right there, I'm moving right there.  - I prefer not.
老师好
Sensei.
准备好 开始
Ready, begin.
我今年刚毕业...
Uh, graduated this year...
...主修地缘政治学 辅修文学
...majored in geo politics, minor text things.
对于政府与科技的对接应用
Very interested in government technologies,
非常感兴趣
as they intersect and co-exist.
塑造 未来
Shape, future.
当初何必把他送去常春藤大学?
Why did we bother sending him to an Ivy College for?
毕业了三个月都找不到一份工作
Three months out of school and he can't find a job.
- 松笨先生  - 松本先生...
- Mr. Matsu-piece-u.  - Matsu Moto...
- 松... 笨  - 松本
- Masi... Moto  - Masu Moto.
- 玛莎 我能叫你玛莎吗?  - 不可以
- Martha, can I call you Martha?  - No, you may not.
杰克 世上有两种人
Okay. Jack, there's two type of people in this world.
思考者和行动者
There's thinkers and there's doers.
还有赢家 梦想家 和伙伴们
There's winners, there's dreamers and there's buddies.
跟我谈谈你的缺点吧
What about, some witnesses.
您的面相看上去 非常值得信赖
You have a very trustworthy face.
就像... 亚洲版的肯德基爷爷
You remind of like a... an Asian Colonel Sanders.
我信任您
A man I can trust.
这种和平时期 你就像是这迷惘的一代
It's a millennial, you know like some kind of lost generation.
联邦调查局为什么找你?
Why was the FBI looking for you?
什么?
The what?
联邦调查局那事 很高兴你提出来
Yeah, FBI getting a flag there.
你十四岁时应该没干过像和一些外星人疯狂的事吧?
Did you ever have any alien craziness when you were fourteen.
他们对我挺好 很快就找到我了
They were very kind to me, found me in a jiffy.
呃 档案里没有记录
Uh, and that's all been expunged.
但其实奥巴马给我颁发了勋章
Obama get me a medal, actually.
话说
Just saying.
聘用一个获得勋章的人 也是一件好事吧
It's always good to have a medal guy in the office, with a medal.
- 奥巴马颁发的?  - 是啊
- From Obama?  - Yeah.
可公司里大部分人都是共和党员
In this office, we're mostly Republicans.
所以
So.
- 我不太舒服  - 是吗
- I'm not feeling to good.  - No.
- 是  - 去找个狗食盆呗?
- No.  - Why don't you get a little dipping tray.
弄点健胃消食片 总会好的
And dip the dog in the pepto, that's the solution.
糟糕 还有一场 得走了 快
Pow, I got another one, we gotta go, come on.
不是吧?
Really?
请坐
Sit.
祝你应聘成功
Got a nice sell from this.
萨姆・威特维奇 刚毕业
Sam Witwicky, recent college graduate.
工作经验基本全无
Previous experience next to zero.
然而 却有一封董事会给的推荐信
Yet, he has a recommend letter from our board.
还真是狗屎运啊
W.T.F. to that.
你们董事会里有我认识的人?
Do I know somebody on your board?
听着 我们无需多介绍了
Here's the deal, we know who we are.
艾奇利塔集团是航天和电信业的领头羊
Accuretta systems is called the leader in telecom, aerospace.
每年盈利十七亿
17 billion on profit last year.
合作对象有国防部 国家航空航天局
We contract for DOP, NASA,
喷气推进实验室等等
JPL you name it.
在这儿可有大把的机遇
You can find here doors open for you.
总之孩子 毕业后的第一份工作十分重要
And what, first job out of college is critical, kid.
要不就是平步青云的第一步
You either take a step down the correct career path.
要不就是一辈子的噩梦深渊
Or you fall into a life sucking abyss.
命运如何 就要取决于你如何回应我接下来的这句话
So it all depends on how you respond to my next two words.
打动我
Impress me.
现在?
Now?
打动我
Impress me.
我都没准备...
You catch me off guard, I...
打动我
Impress me.
我没什么好遮掩的 您随便问
I'm an open book, ask me any question you like.
- 你是个有野心 很强势的人  - 是的
- So you're a go get a ramrod.  - Yes sir.
控制欲很强
Take charge kind of guy.
我像杀手一般冷血无情
I'm a killer, a stone cold killer.
喔 控制狂
So, take charge guy.
如同海盗 野蛮人一般强势
Take charge, Viking, barbarian.
我就是这样的
Of course, it's me.
我行! 故我在
Pow! I'm here.
我们不需要这种人
We are not looking for that here.
别奉承 别拍马屁
No brown nosing, no suck up.
别像个仆人...
No toolery, I...
布拉索斯先生你好
Yes, Mr. Brazos.
为什么香岱儿用的是 本该在红色楼层
Um, why is Chantal using what appears to be,
才能用的红杯子呢?
a red cup from the red floor?
- 我们这层是黄色主题  - 立刻处理
- When we are on the yellow floor.  - I'm on it.
这简直是从视觉到身心的背叛
It is a visual and therefore a visceral betrayal.
办了它
Stop it.
傻女人
Such a dumb ass.
恶心
Disgusting.
谢谢
Thank you.
简直太混乱了
It's a total anarchy around here.
邮件说招的是行政助理
The uh, email I read said administrative aid.
不 是递送员
Nope, mail room.
那我走了
I'm going to go.
你知道有多少名校毕业的
Uh, do you have any idea how many Ivy league,
荣誉学生们求着来...
Phi Beta Kappa's would kill...
先生我救过两次你的命
Mister I saved your life twice.
我确实不能告诉你时间 经过
Okay, I can't tell you how or when.
或原因 但我做过无比重要的事情
Or why, but I have done shit that matters.
我只是想再做点有意义的事情
And I'd just kinda like a job where I matter again.
谢谢 但我不感谢您
So thank you, but no thank you.
- 好吗  - 知道我怎么想的吗?
- Okay. -You know what I think?
干大事前总有琐事
You want the job after this job.
孩子啊 你得先干这份眼下唯一的差事
But son, this is the job that's standing in your way.
所以你得把它做好 做的非常非常好
And that's why you're going to be so very, very good at it.
我看着你的时候
'Cause when I look at you.
我仿佛看见年轻的自己
I see a younger me.
"鹰巢"秘密总部 华盛顿特区
在勤汽车人请注意
All running Autobots in car,
一刻钟后开始训练
training in 15 minutes.
恐龙到23号车位报到
Dino report to bay 23.
横炮到37号车位进行武器评估
Sideswipe bay 37 for weapons assessment.
议员 我想您应该知道 国家航空航天局...
Senator, I suggest you remember that when the NASA...
...需要资金时得找我
...wants funding they call me.
中情局若想消灭某个目标
When the CIA is going to take out a target.
也得先获得我的许可
They ask first for my permission.
总统若想了解...
When the President wants to know...
...议员的动态
...which members of Congress are politically vulnerable.
比方说 某些不为人知的罪行
In terms of oh, let's say undiscovered criminal conduct.
都会来问我
I'm on their memory dials.
政府宣称正追踪此爆炸案
USA agency say they have been monitoring the blast.
但事实上 这是一场秘密的军事袭击
But in fact this was a covert military strike.
无国家或组织宣称对此负责
No nation has yet claimed ownership.
中情局追着我屁股问...
The CIA is up my ass about this mystery...
...中东这事
...raid in the middle east.
尽早坦白了吧 咱们与此有关吗?
So it's time to come clean, was the unit involved?
我不确定 女士
Uh, I'm not sure, Ma'am.
看着 你们可以这样射伤...
All right guys, this is how you do a Decepticon...
...敌人的头部
...head kill shot.
作为情报局头头
As director of National Intelligence,
我讨厌模棱两可的回答
I'm a really big fan of intelligent answers.
我... 我也不能确定
I... I can't really tell you definitively.
汽车人们就像小鬼
These Autobots are like teenage kids.
他们喜欢偶尔出去偷个乐
They like to sneak out of the house once in a while.
雷尼克斯上校 你到底是不是这儿的指挥官?
Colonel Lennox, are you in command or are you not?
我是的...
Yes, Ma'am. I am...
别叫我女士了 听够了
Stop with the Ma'am, enough with the Ma'am.
我看起来那么老?
Do I look like a Ma'am?
不老 女士
No, ma'am.
是的女士 不喊了
Yes, ma'am, yes.
- 这东西是我最好的发明  - 是啊
- This one is a perfect invention I have made.  - Right.
喔 你们终于来了
Oh, good they're here.
我叫齐 希望你们能给他个交代
My name's Que. I do hope you have answers for him.
从没见他这么沮丧
I've never seen him so upset.
擎天柱 你还记得夏洛特・米樱吗?
Optimus, you remember Charlotte Mearing?
国家情报局主管
Our director of National Intelligence.
他心情不太好
He's in a bad mood.
他不想跟任何人说话
He's a not want to talk-a to anybody today.
什么意思?
What is this?
无声的抗议?
The silent treatment?
我们已见识过了 可不像这样
We've seen that, and this is not that.
- 没那么夸张吧  - 这比那严重
- Definitely not.  - This is worse.
老大 别这么不中用了
Prime, make something of yourself.
他生气了
He's pissed.
你骗我们
You lied to us.
有关我们星球的一切进展...
Everything humans' know of our planet...
...你说过都会告诉我们
...we were told had all been shared.
那为何这个会在人类手里?
So why was this found in human possession?
我们起初也不知晓
We were in the dark on this also.
目前这事在第七区 也就只有主管知道
It was director only clearance at Sector 7, until now.
- 给我包  - 哪个包?
- The bag.  - Which bag?
爱马仕铂金包 绿色鸵鸟皮的那个
Hermes Birkin, green ostrich.
真受不了
Oh my god.
这事只有极少数人知道
This is a secret few men knew.
并且还活着的人 更是少之又少
And fewer still remain alive.
请允许我向你介绍
Allow me to please introduce to you,
两位国家航空航天局得行动组主管
two of NASA's founding mission directors.
以及宇航员 巴兹 奥尔德林
and astronaut, Dr. Buzz Aldrin.
他是当年首次登月的两人之一
One of the first two men to step foot on the moon. Sir.
这位是擎天柱
Optimus Prime.
你我都曾遨游太空
From a fellow space traveler.
很荣幸见到你
It's a true honor.
我也十分荣幸
The honor is mine.
我们60年代的整个太空竞赛计划...
Our entire space race of the 1960's...
...都是为了一件事
...it appears was in response to an event.
为了让宇航员们调查一艘坠毁的外星船舰
Our astronauts investigated a crashed alien ship.
船上无幸存者
No survivors on board.
上级要求我们严守秘密
We were sworn to secrecy by our commander in chief.
你们不得泄露本次任务
This was a mission you will never speak of.
遵命 长官
I understand, sir.
一共只有35人知道航空航天局的真正计划
A total of 35 people knew the real plan at NASA.
当时苏联已经能进行无人探测器登陆
Soviets managed to land unmanned probes.
机缘巧合 他们肯定得到了燃料棒
Somehow they must have picked up that fuel rod.
我们相信 苏联科学家...
We believe the Russians deduced...
推断出燃料棒 是裂变燃料的部件
that the rod was a fissionable fuel assembly.
并掌握其控制方法 把它用在了切尔诺贝利核电站
Believed they had it mastered and harnessed it at Chernobyl.
我们共进行了六次任务
We went on six missions in all.
采集了数百张照片 并提取了样品
We took hundreds of photos and samples.
随后我们把它们封锁起来
We locked them away forever.
并叫停了探月计划
And the moon program was shut down.
你们是在哪里搜寻到了坠毁的太空舱?
Where did you search the crash hold?
那艘被命名为方舟的飞船
The ships name was the Ark.
我目送它逃离塞伯坦星球
I watched it escape Cybertron myself.
飞船上承载着一项...
It was carrying an Autobot...
...汽车人的尖端技术 能让我们赢得战争
...technology which would have won us the war.
此外 还有飞船上的船长
And its captain.
- 船长是谁?  - 他就是伟大的御天敌
- Who was this captain?  - The Great Sentinel Prime.
汽车人技术的发明者
The technology's inventor.
他是汽车人的前任领袖
He was commander of the Autobots.
随后才是我
Before me.
我必须抢...
It's imperative that I find it...
...在霸天虎之前找到太空舱
...before the Decepticons learn of its location.
我们汽车人的飞船完全有能力找到
Our Autobot space craft has the ability to get there.
所以 你最好祈祷现在还来得及
And, you must pray it's in time.
你好 我是来找卡莉・斯宾塞的
Hi, I'm here to see Carly Spenser.
卡莉呀!
Carly!
你得到那工作了?
You got the job?
- 说来你都不信  - 你真得到那工作了?
- This is crazy.  - You really got it?
- 对  - 我说的没错 都是幸运兔子的功劳
- Yes.  - See what did I tell you, it's the bunny.
你太客气了
You are so welcome.
- 你有没有更喜欢我了?  - 一点点啦
- Do you like me a little more?  - A little bit, yeah.
我想见传说中的...
I'm seriously curious about...
...高人
...this space mountain.
我知道 这儿很漂亮 不是吗?
I know, isn't it beautiful in here?
他可是有史以来最酷的人
And he's the coolest guy, ever.
- 嗯  - 没错
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
萨姆啊
Sam.
我是迪兰・古尔德
Dylan Gould.
很荣幸见到你
Pleasure to meet you.
我也是
Pleasure meeting you.
卡莉经常和我说起你
Carly has told me a lot about you.
彼此彼此 你这幢楼真漂亮
Well, visa versa. It's a beautiful building you got.
就像星际舰艇企业一样
The Star Ship Enterprise here.
非常感谢 过奖了
Thank you very much, it leaks.
啊 卡莉来这边帮忙整理收藏品之前...
Ah, before Carly came to help on the collection...
...这里就是一个烂摊子
...it was just a complete mess.
现在再看看 井井有条啊
But now the restorations are back on track.
今年我要去趟圆石滩
I'm going to pebble beach this year,
再捧一尊那样的奖杯回来
going to need a trophy for that stand right there.
知道原因吗?
You know why?
原因就是眼前这位女士
Because this woman right here,
...就是我的秘密武器
...is my secret weapon. Okay.
古尔德先生 您真是过奖了
Mr. Gould please, you exaggerate.
我只是负责组织工作
All I've done is get you organized.
噢 你的功劳可不止那些 我的公爵夫人
Oh you have done much more than that, my Dutchess.
小昵称哦 有意思
Nicknames, that's fun.
对 我的公爵夫人
Yeah, the Dutchess.
太可爱了
She's adorable.
要知道当初我把她从英国大使馆挖过来时
You know when I stole her away from the British Embassy,
我对她说 处理国家事务太没挑战了
I said, it's easy to manage a country.
为何不来管理无价的艺术收藏品呢?
Try managing a priceless collection of art.
看看这辆1939年的德拉海165敞篷车
Take a look at this 1939 Delahaye 165 Cabriolet.
由一位法国人设计
Designed by a French man.
看看这线条 多优雅呀 是吧?
Look at the curves, elegant isn't it?
漂亮
Beautiful.
性感
Sensual.
让人想起完美女性的身体曲线
Built to evoke the body of the ideal woman.
跟我来
Come on.
我的父亲只靠一张十美元的办公桌和一个梦想
My dad had a ten dollar desk and a dream.
白手起家 建立了一个商业帝国
And he built it into an empire.
我们拥有全美最大的会计事务所
We're the largest accounting firm in the US.
在他去世后我开始了我的历险
I started off the adventure side after he passed.
投资未来
That's in the future.
看谁是未来的赢家
Try and bet on the winners.
收集汽车让我保持理性
See collecting cars helps me keep my sanity.
这些照片不错
These look great.
哦 古尔德先生 那天你真了不起
Oh, that was a great day, Mr. Gould.
- 我之前都没注意到这张  - 我也没
- I didn't see that one.  - No, me either.
那次比赛太激烈了
Jeans are tight.
哦 又来了 又来了
Oh, here we go, here we go.
看见没?
You see that?
对我的车评头论足还不够
Judgment, judge to my car.
你还想继续在那看他对我评头论足?
You going to wait on him while he's judging me?
你这是怎么了? 他可是我老板
What's with you? He's my boss.
我们吃住的花费还得靠他呢
He still pays for our food, our rent.
行 我全明白了
No, I totally understand.
我知道你的意思 我吃软饭的嘛
I'm totally fine, I get it. I'm well fed.
告诉你吧 我可不用让你养了
Guess what, I'm not your boy toy anymore.
我现在也独立自主了
I got my big boy pants on now.
你懂?
You see them?
请上车 公爵夫人
In the car, thank you Duchess.
噢 老天啊 你觉得他威胁到你了?
Oh, my god, are you threatened by him?
威胁 他怎么威胁到我?
Threatened, what am I threatened by?
靠他的钱 他的权势 还是他长得比我帅?
His money, his power, his good looks?
以上皆非 仅此而已!
None of the above, check!
你发起飙来真性感
Your temper tantrums are so sexy.
快上车 拜托了
Get in the car, please.
萨姆 他又不是第一个冲我笑的男人
Sam, he's hardly the first man to ever smile at me.
我自有分寸
I think I can handle it.
等等 让我不爽的是... 是你也对他笑了
Hold on, hold on. It's... It's the smiling back part that gets me.
- 好不好  - 那我不对他笑了
- Okay.  - No more smiles.
我保证再也不了
Never again, I promise.
这我爱听
You see, that works for me.
别急 别急
Easy, easy.
你那样发动不了车的
You're not going to get it started that way.
我只是在做准备
What, I was just getting it ready.
我现在已经做好32%的准备工作了
I'm about 32% done with my restoration.
铝合金边油斗 在车尾加个副翼就好了
Chrome work, put a spoiler on the back, done deal.
卡莉跟我说你在为工作头疼
You know Carly's been telling me you've been struggling job loss.
你要知道
Just so you know.
我是艾奇利塔公司的董事
I'm on the board for Accuretta systems.
我帮你打个电话
And I put in a call for you.
决不泄露 如何
Just keep it between us, okay.
她对我真好
She's so kind to me.
你真是个幸运的家伙
You're a lucky man.
苍耳号接近静海基地
Xanthium approaching Tranquility base.
这里是休斯顿指挥中心 批准苍耳号行动
Here's Houston, you're a go Xanthium.
阿姆斯特朗 祝你愉快
Armstrong, having a good day.
救护车 我们行动吧
Ratchet, let's roll.
他们带上那顶魔法帽了吗?
Did they get that mag cap on?
准备接近目标
Copy contact.
我们正进入方舟号
We're entering the Ark.
他的生命值很低
His levels are faint.
自我封锁
Locked himself away.
只为了保护能量柱
To guard the pillars.
御天敌
Sentinel.
回家吧 老朋友
You're coming home, old friend.
威震天万岁
All hail, Megatron.
我的主人 是主人来了
My master, it's master.
啊 别贪心
Ah, don't be greedy.
脆弱的小家伙们
My fragile ones.
主人 你看起来不怎么好啊
You look poor, Master.
您受了这么重伤 我太心疼了
How it pains me to see you so vulnerable, so weak.
闭嘴 你这个马屁精
Spare me you gaseous sycophant.
你知道你该做什么 却玩忽职守
You know what you were told. Resist nothing.
声波报到 威震天主人
Soundwave reporting, Lord Megatron.
我的刺客 有什么消息吗?
And what news from my assassin?
汽车人上钩了
Autobots have taken the bait.
他们发现了方舟号
They discovered the Ark,
带着货物返回了
and returned with its cargo.
干得漂亮 追踪那条船到月球
You did me great honor, tracking that ship to the moon.
声波 你的人类盟友们已经没有利用价值了
Your human collaborators have served their purpose, Soundwave.
是时候灭口了
It's time to eliminate loose ends.
激光鸟 把他们全干掉
Laserbeak, kill them all.
乐此不疲
With pleasure.
你爸在家?
Is your daddy home?
然后爸爸说这是我们的时代了
Then the daddy said it's our time.
妈妈 你好
Hello, mom.
滚出我们家!
Get out of the house!
- 你来我家做什么?  - 拜访而已
- What are you doing in my house?  - Just visiting.
艾奇利塔系统
你来我家做什么?
What's this hoochee around here?
拜访而已...
Just because...
不行 这是航天部
No. This is the aerospace baby.
你再也不准回来了
You are not allowed back here.
新来的 你看?
New guy, you see that?
堕落的拉丁人
That's a Latin melt down, okay.
你在我的办公室里敢穿奇装异服 我就炒了你
You ever show up in my office with a regional outfit you're fired.
听到了吗?
You got that, okay?
要是你打算在这里待上两年半
If you're going to be on this job for 2 1/2 years, okay.
那么我要你吃喝拉撒都得带着这小车
I want you to live it, love it and made it.
在我这里没有捷径可走 我可是相当严格
There's no ladder climbing in my office. I run a tight ship.
- 知道了 先生  - 好 干活
- Yes, sir.  - Okay, so move.
我找到之前和你说的那份报告了
I found that paper I was telling you about.
你在看谁呢?
What are we looking at?
闭嘴!
Shut up!
你再敢对我那样小心我揍你
You do that to me again and I'll kick your ass.
- 你好啊 美女  - 你好啊
- Hi Angel.  - Hello.
你还好吧?
You're good?
我要去市中心开会 顺路进来看下你 没问题吧?
I had a meeting downtown, is it okay for me to stop by?
没想到这本500页的...
I don't know my 500 page...
...员工行为手册 读起来是这么乏味
...employee conduct manual isn't exactly a page turner.
悲剧啊
This is grey.
汽车人拯救世界
Autobots are out there saving the world,
我在这整理四个文件夹
and I organize four binders.
这就是梦想 跟我来
It may be a dream, come on.
你违反访客条例了
Visitor violation.
你没事吧?
You okay?
没事
Absolutely.
到我了
I'm next.
听我说 在星期六
Listen, Saturday.
有个工作性质的聚会
There's a party at the house it's a work thing,
但是迪兰也邀请你了
but Dylan's invited you too.
噢 是吗
Really, oh did he.
不要挖苦我
No need to come off with bad jokes.
这对我真的很重要
It would really mean a lot to me, okay.
我愿意去 你怎么过去?
I'd love to go. How did you get over here?
开车去啊
A car.
你又没车
You don't have a car.
不 我有
Yes I do.
怎么 你中大奖了吗?
What, did you win it in a raffle?
呃 他送了辆车给我
Uh, he gave me one.
他送了辆车给你?
He gave you a car?
对 我想是对我工作的激励吧
Yeah, I think it was a work perk.
嗯 工作的激励
Hmm, a work perk.
他给你什么车?
What kind of car did he gave you?
嗯 奔驰SLS-AMG跑车
Um, a Mercedes SLS AMG.
引擎太带劲了
Really crazy engine.
梅塞尔斯奔驰SLS
Mercedes Benz SLS.
你开这车过来的?
You rode this here?
这车值20万美金呢
It's a $200,000 Car.
我知道
I know.
你知道我要工作多久才能买得起这么辆车吗?
You know how long it would take me to afford a car like this?
- 很久  - 对 要53年
- Long time.  - Yeah like, 53 years.
刚才你也同意这是为了激励我的工作
I said it was a perk, first.
你知道我们该怎么做吗? 我们应该把它卖了然后买套房子
You know what we should do? We should sell it and buy a house.
你受打击了 我明白
You're frustrated, I know.
我知道那种感受
I've been there.
但这只是我的工作酬劳
It's called paying your dues.
情况会好起来的
Good things will happen.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
我需要有人牺牲午餐的时间做文档归类
I need some lunchtime filing done, stat.
谁想给我布鲁斯・布拉索斯留下好印象?
Who would like to score some Bruce Brazos points?
布鲁斯 这就是你想要的人
Bruce, you found your guy.
威特维奇啊
Witwicky.
公司的运转全仰仗他
The man who makes this company run.
看看这是谁 你姐妹 还是网友?
Now who have we here, a sister, facebook friend?
微博上认识的吗
Twitter, tweeter.
- 卡莉 这是布鲁斯  - 你好
- Carly this is Bruce. Bruce.  - Hi.
我是他女朋友 幸会幸会
I'm his girlfriend, pleasure to meet you.
萨姆说的对 你的发型很帅
Sam was right, you really do have smashing head of hair.
- 多谢夸奖  - 不客气
- Well thank you.  - Your welcome.
萨姆 我该走了
Sam I gotta run.
给 你的礼物
Here, your present.
你喜欢的颜色
Your favorite color.
幸会了 布拉索斯先生
Nice to meet you Mr. Brazos.
幸会
And you.
回见 伙计们
See ya boys.
打翻我的文件夹 你怎么解释 杰瑞?
I'm still stewing about that binder incident, Jerry.
能等我喝完舒化奶再说吗
May I finish my Chu Wah milk, Tony.
我才不关心你那变态的牛奶
I don's care about your exotic milk.
我关心的是你对我不尊重
I care about respect.
我知道你的来历
I know who you are.
你是威特维奇
Wicky, Witwicky.
- 我知道你 我在和你说话  - 借过
- You know who, I'm talking to you.  - Excuse me.
谢谢
Thank you.
别 别 慢点 猛男
No, no, slow down tiger.
六张不同照片的背景里都有你
You showed up on the background of six different photos.
出现过外星人的两大洲
Two contains of aliens.
我还发现你去过埃及
That was you in Egypt.
哈 对了吧
Huh, right.
因为你认识那些外星人
Because you know the Aliens.
回见
See ya.
还我外套
Give me my jacket.
嘿 我姓王 王深
Hey, I am Wang, Deep Wang.
王深
Deep Wang.
你怎么还不懂 "深喉"(线人)
You're not getting it, "Deep Throat".
好了 因为他们告诉你了
Okay, cause they told you.
小点声 他们正在监视
Shhh, they watch and listen.
我不能去政府
I can't go to the government.
你可以的 因为事情快包不住了
You, you can because shit's going down.
小子 代号是皮克 是弗洛伊德里的
Son, it is code Pink as in 'Floyd '.
月球黑暗面 为什么自1972年之后 就再也没有人登陆过那里吗
Dark side, why do you think no ones been up there since 1972.
你说的是英语 但是听不懂的英语
You speak in English, it's a very strange English.
那是为什么 额... 哦
That's why un. Oh... oh.
别 我要不客气了
Don't, I'm gonna hit ya.
那我也会对你不客气了 小子
Well I'm going to hit ya right back, son.
这是我的声明书
That's my manifesto.
你把这个带出去
Your riding this out.
他们要干掉每个知道黑暗面内情的人
They are wiping us out. Everyone who knows this is in the dark.
你的外星朋友们有危险
Your alien friends is in danger.
他们就要靠你去拯救了
You know the good ones, it's up to you.
别激动 萨姆
Easy, Sam.
有什么好看的?
What are you looking at?
哎呦 蠢货
Yow, dog.
你刚刚偷看我的大便吗?
Did you look at my shit?
你老板是谁?
Who are you working for?
看我们谁能瞪过谁
Stare down, you and me.
我看我已经赢了
Guess I won.
月球... 项目
Moons... list.
更多的搁置计划
More suspends program.
专家死亡
Experts dead.
太空项目终止
Space Program ends.
黑暗面
Dark side.
月球的黑暗面
Dark side of the moon.
看看我在洗手间外面找到什么了?
Look what I found outside the bathroom, huh?
是你的吗? 处理下这个
It yours? Deal with this.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
你要的事情 我都做了
I did everything you want.
我真觉得我们应该谈谈
I really think we should talk,
因为有些事情...
because some of the stuff...
喔 先敲门
Whoa, knock first.
你没看到我很忙吗
Can't you see I'm busy.
你是谁 你是谁啊?
Who are you, who are you?
你刚才在厕所里骑着我
You straddled me in the stall.
这是史无前例的 我永生难忘
That's happened to me once in this life, I wouldn't forget it.
- 没有 不记得了  - 在厕所的隔间里
- No, no.  - In the bathroom stall.
你把你的东西掏了出来
You pulled your package out.
喔 我 我们不是同性恋好么
Whoa, whoa, we are not boyfriends, okay.
一个电话我就能抄了你
One phone call from me and I'll have you fired.
哦 是的 我说到做到 死同性恋
Oh yes I will, Gaylord.
你没事吧?
You okay?
我痔疮犯了
It's a hemorrhoid.
我是不是应该再过来? 什么时候需要我过来?
Should I come back? When should I come back?
当你学会礼貌了之后再回来
Come back when you learn some manners.
我不认识他 我什么都不会说
I don't know him, I would never say anything.
事实会证明的 就像我承诺的那样
no one would touch the dark side, just like I promised.
我绝不透漏半个字
I will blend them into the program bogus
你还想让我怎么样
What more do you want from me?
杰瑞呀
Jerry.
我最喜欢你了
You are my favorite.
你让我做什么都行
I'll do whatever you want me to do.
我知道
I know.
我的上级需要我...
My superiors need me to....
- 干什么?  - 让你自杀
- What?  - Suicide you.
你和威特维奇说什么了?
What did you say to Witwicky?
去你的
Shit.
哈 想来顿电子鸟大餐吗 混蛋
Huh, who want's some chicken dinner now, bitch?
因为今天有人惹毛老子我了
'Cause somebody messed with the wrong Wang today.
来啊 你不是要杀我吗
Come on, you want some of me.
我不想在听到查克训斥般的废话了
I don't need anymore didactic lectures from Chuck.
天啊!
Jesus!
叫法律部门的人过来
Get it legal.
那是杰瑞
That's Jerry.
别看了 是啊 一个同事死了
Come on, people. Yes, a workmate died.
但是往窗外看也不能让他起死回生
But looking out windows is not going to bring him back.
这个人太抑郁了
The man was depressed.
别照相
Don't take a picture.
你可以就这么一直看他 但是他还是活不了
You can keep watching him but he's not getting up.
都知道鸡蛋矮子吧?
You all read Humpty Dumpty.
好了
Okay.
喂 威特维奇
Witwicky.
这件事的新闻发布会之前
When this comes out in the press,
你要把老王的东西清理干净
you clean up. Wang is everywhere.
他摔得稀烂
He is in the bristle. He's in the bamboo.
血溅得到处都是
He's on the balustrade.
看到下面的人行道了吗?
Did you see the sidewalk down there?
天啊
Oh, man.
别再想起这个人 他的名字 甚至停车位
You forget his person, get his name off his parking space.
嘿 我们什么时候买了一个新的影印机
Hey, when did we get a new copier?
他说了关于我看见的任何事吗?
See, I'm not gonna say anything about what I saw?
你和谁在一个坑里上厕所完全是你的事
Who you share a toilet stall with is totally your business.
这肯定是日本货
This is exceedingly Japanese.
他们从来都是把东西设计的很复杂
They never make it easy.
你这是怎么弄的?
What is with you?
出大事了 卡莉
This is the really deal, Carly.
好了 我需要你保持镇定
Okay, I need you to stay composed.
这是真的 我一会儿在给你解释
It's real life, I'll explain to you later.
我有急事找雷尼克斯上校
We got an emergency, you gotta get Colonel Lennox in here.
是关于霸天虎的 霸天虎要回来了
On point decepticons, the deceptions are back again.
- 你现在就要让我进去  - 冷静点 先生
- You gotta open that gate up right now.  - Easy, sir.
这是公共健康与社会福利部
This is health and human services.
那你怎么拿着冲锋枪?
Right, packing M-4's?
你们在保护输尿管
What are you protecting, colostomy bags?
- 尿壶还有止咳剂吗?  - 亲爱的
- Bed pans, throat lozenges?  - Babe.
你从哪里搞来那个帽子的? 护士学校吗?
Where did you get that hat from? Nursing school?
所以你们在保护护士和脚气药粉啊
So your are nurses and foot powder protector.
- 哦 多棒啊 是啊  - 亲爱的 我觉得我们没有...
- Oh, fantastic, yes.  - Baby, I don't think we're in...
- ...来对地方  - 就是这里没错
- ...the right place.  - We are in the right place.
这就是我们要找的地方
We are in the right place.
我们就是要来这里
We are in the right place,
我现在要找擎天柱
and I want to talk to Optimus right now.
你现在就把擎天柱给我找来
You're going to get me Optimus right now.
我确定你找错地方了
I'm sure you got the wrong building.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你明不明白霸天虎就要回来了?
What part of the Deceptions are back don't you understand?
学聪明点
You're being a smart ass.
别碰我的车 这是个古董车
Do not hit my car, it's a collector's item.
我要是你 就不会往前开
I wouldn't do that.
你疯了啊
You're crazy.
检测到有能量块
We got an Energon reading.
探测到在车上
We got Missed it by that much in the vehicle.
- 不许动!  - 哇 哇 哇 我们没有动
- Freeze!  - Whoa, whoa, whoa, we're freezing.
你们是在...
Are you...
快从车上下来
Please get out of the car.
- 我抓住他了 过来  - 大黄蜂!
- I got him, go.  - Bee!
大黄蜂听到了吗?
Is Bee in there?
- 好了 你抓住我了  - 趴下
- Okay, you got me.  - Stay down.
你们就是这样对待汽车人的吗?
This how you treat Autobots?
我们可是一伙的
We're on the same team.
你们今后还是去便利店打杂吧 白痴
Yeah, enjoy your next job at 7-11, dickhead.
- 没错  - 混蛋
- That's right.  - A-hole.
现在车毁了吧?
How's your car now?
这才是我的车
That's my car.
过来
Come here.
过来!
Come here!
别这样... 萨姆
Come on... Sam.
你怎么回事?
What is your deal, huh?
我知道你在执行秘密军事行动
I know your black ops stuff is important.
我知道那很重要
You know I'm not trying to diminish it,
我也不是要责怪你
or guilt trip you, or anything.
但是你之后一直不见踪迹
But I just never see you anymore.
你就不能回车库待一晚上吗?
You can't come to the garage and stay on one night?
萨姆 你这么说让我很难受
Sam, that makes me feel bad.
是啊 我希望你难受 你应该难受
Yeah, well, I hope you feel bad, you should feel bad.
你看看我现在开的老爷车
Look at the jalopy I'm driving now.
我每天都感觉很难受
I feel bad every single day.
呦 你们俩个 我们走
Yo, let's go, both of you.
雷尼克斯上校想见你们
Lennox wants to see you.
什么 你们不再阻拦我们了吗?
What, we're not good enough for you anymore.
对不起 宝贝 他们太粗鲁了
Sorry, babe, they were very rude, right.
你要把我的车修好
And you're fixing my car.
听见了吗?
You don't think so?
如果你今天...
Raise your hand if you had a...
...被一个会飞的变态忍者复印机杀 你也会举手
...flying psycho ninja copier try to kill you today.
那是我的铜指环(一种武器)
Those are my brass knuckles.
那是我的腿镯 我是不是也要把这个脱掉?
That's my anklet, do I have to take that off too?
还有我的趾环?
And my toe rings?
撤走地面所有展示机
All the unofficials clear the floor.
十分钟后连线
We have ten minutes until attempted contact.
我们已经获得了...
We've taken possession of...
...御天敌藏在太空舱中的五个装置
...the five devices that were hidden in the ship of Sentinel Prime.
它们好像是某种汽车人的科技原型
They're some kind of prototype Autobot technology.
他们说御天敌是他们文明的爱因斯坦
They say Sentinel was the Einstein of his civilization.
所以我们要把它们保管好
So we're going to keep these locked up,
...直到我们知道如何处理它们
...until we know what we're dealing with.
现在谁也不许接近它们
Right now no one gets access.
- 谁也不行  - 今天早上一个人认出我来了
- No one.  - This morning a guy recognized me.
他告诉我来警告你们
He told me to warn you,
他谈到了月球的黑暗面
he's talking about the dark side of the moon.
- 然后霸天虎杀了他  - 等下 你刚提到了月球?
- Then they killed him.  - Wait a minute, you mentioned the moon?
是的 月球的黑暗面
Yeah, dark side of the moon.
但是为什么霸天虎谋杀人类呢?
But why would the decepticons want to kill humans?
我以为他们的敌人是汽车人
I thought their war was with the Autobots.
他做了这份快速报告
And that is when he made his first quick list of time report.
正是我需要的...
That's what I want...
这个女的是谁
Who's the chick, okay.
不好意思 雷尼克斯上校
Excuse me, Colonel Lennox.
米樱局长
Director Mearing.
这是萨姆・威特维奇
This is Sam Witwicky.
- 一个老百姓...  - 我知道他的名字 上校
- A civilian c...  - I know his name, Colonel.
我想知道谁准许他进来的
I want to know who gave him clearance.
谁准许我进来的? 要是擎天柱可以吗
Who gave me Clearance? How about Optimus Prime.
当他降落在周边后就去找我的家
When he touched down in suburbia looking for my house.
这是国家情报局局长
This is the national intelligence director.
你最好...
In case you...
- 嗨  - 你这是无视联邦长官
- Hi.  - Disrespecting a federal officer.
凭这个应该把你带走 她是谁
That ought to get you somewhere, who's she?
她是我女朋友
She's my girlfriend.
到这来是约会的吗?
What is this like a date?
她知道所有关于汽车人的事
She knows all about the Autobots, okay.
她知道大黄蜂 而且来自军事世家
She knows Bumblebee, and comes from a military family.
我可以为她担保
I can vouch for her.
嘿 大伙儿
Hey, I have an idea.
说正事行不行?
How bout we get back to the important topics?
例如像我差点被一个霸天虎把脸撕下去
Like the fact I almost had my face cut off by a Decepticon.
作为纳税人 我可以投诉的事实上
As a tax payer I can lodge a complaint as a matter of fact.
好了 听着
Okay, listen.
今天萨姆办公室的一个软件工程师被谋杀了
One of the software engineers at Sam's office was murdered today.
他曾经参与了美国航天局月球影像探测器项目
He was involved in NASA's Lunar mapping probe.
现在的情况是这样的 雷尼克斯上校
Here's the thing, Colonel Lennox.
我们不能把国家安全托付给这些乳臭未干的小孩儿
We cannot entrust national security to teenagers.
除非是我漏看了官方批准他参与的文件
Unless I missed the policy paper.
有什么文件我没看到吗?
Are we doing that now?
没有 很好
No, good.
我不管你是谁
I don't care who you are.
如果你透漏半点你看到的东西
If you breathe a word of what you've seen here.
你就会被定为叛国罪
You will do time for treason.
你明白了吗?
Do you understand me?
我只听汽车人的命令
I'll take my orders from the Autobots.
我认他们 不认你
I know them, I don't know you.
你会认得的
You will.
御天敌
Sentinel Prime.
他看上去也是靠能量块存活 但他的能量已经耗尽了
He seems to run on Energon, and he's out of it.
他处于一种睡眠模式
He's in a sort of a sleep mode.
我们开始吧
Let us begin.
这是源能矩阵
It's the great matrix of leadership.
宇宙中唯一可以...
He holds the only thing in the...
...重新启动变形金刚的至宝
...universe that can repower a Transformers spark.
真是令人难以置信啊
This is incredible.
御天敌
Sentinel Prime.
醒来吧
We bid you return.
复仇
Revenge.
- 别  - 别开火
- No.  - Hold your fire.
- 不 御天敌  小心
- No, Sentinel.  - Hold your fire.
是我 擎天柱
It is I, Optimus Prime.
一切都过去了
It is all right.
你安全了
You are safe.
没什么可怕的了
There's nothing to fear.
我们都在这里
We are here.
你到家了 御天敌
You are home, Sentinel.
那战争呢?
The war?
战争呢!
The war!
战争失败了
The war was lost.
塞伯坦现在只是个贫瘠的荒地
Cybertron is now but a barren wasteland.
我们现在在地球星球上寻求庇护
We have taken refuge here on Planet Earth.
地球上的人类是我们的盟友
Its human race is our allies.
我的飞船呢?
My ship?
我们遭到了攻击
We came under fire.
能量柱
The pillars.
能量柱在哪里?
Where are the pillars?
你保存下来了五个
You saved five of them.
包括主能量柱
Including the control pillar.
才五个?
Only five?
我们一度有好几百呢
We once had hundreds.
打扰一下 先生们 我想问问
Excuse me, gentlemen. May I ask,
你们所寻找的技术到底是什么?
what is this technology you're looking for?
是一种能够重塑宇宙的力量
It is the ability to reshape the universe.
聚合能量柱 形成太空桥
Together the pillars form a space bridge.
这是我设计的 且只有我能掌控
I designed and I alone can control it.
它违背了你们的物理定律...
It defied your laws of physics...
...使得物质能够穿梭于时空
...to transport matter through time and space.
你说的是电子传输装置 对吧?
You're talking about a teleportation device, aren't you?
没错 可以传输资源 和难民
Yes, for resources, for refuges.
难民还是军队和士兵
Refuges or troops of soldiers.
武器 也许还有炸弹
Weapons, maybe bombs.
可以用来突袭
A means of an instant strike,
这就是它的军事用途 对吧?
that's its military function, isn't it?
这是我们的技术
It is our technology.
它必须回归原主
And it must be returned.
是的 如果人类同意的话
Yes, if humans say so.
你们不能...
You can't just bring weapons...
...把大规模杀伤性武器带到我们的地盘
...of mass destruction into our atmosphere.
这得首先经过我们的允许才行
Kind of have to declare customs first.
起码也要提交正式书面申请
A little formality called paperwork.
这是我们人类和动物的区别
Kinda separates us from the animals.
如果你尊重我的权威
I will overlook your condescending tone
我就原谅你的傲慢
if you heave the gravity of mine.
霸天虎们一定不能知道太空桥在这儿
The decepticons must never know the space bridge is here.
因为一旦落入他们手中...
For in their hands...
...将意味着你们星球的毁灭
...it would mean the end of your world.
汇总我的一手资料
Totaly nightmare file.
调查已经开始
So the investigation is open.
我们派了特工去你的办公室
We sent agents to your office.
还有暂时
And for the time being,
我们会派汽车人保护你回家
we're going to send you home with Autobot protection.
我... 我该跟谁说
Wh... Who do I need to speak to,
你们才明白我可以帮得上忙
to get you guys to understand I can help.
我能贡献价值
I can contribute.
嘿 我们都可以帮忙 或者告诉我你所知道的
Hey, we can all help. You tell me what you know,
我就给你讲我去过的所有有趣的星球
I can tell you all the fun planets I've been.
请从我的桌上下去
Get off my desk, please.
喔 你把枪拿出来了 好吧 这样我就帮不了你了
Aw, you pulling out guns. Okay, can't help you on that.
我的天
Oh, my god.
你想让我做什么? 立马打道回府?
What do you envision for me? I go back home now?
然后去复印文件吗? 我是说...
I go back to work? I make copies? I mean...
这里是资深情报官...
This is a unit for veteran...
...和特种部队的工作单位 不是小青年的俱乐部
...intelligence officers and special forces.
即便你开过靓车
Not for boys who once owned special cars.
这么说有点绝情 是吧夫人?
That's a bit harsh, isn't it ma'am?
不要叫我夫人 我不是
Don't call me ma'am, I'm not a ma'am.
可你是个女人 不是吗?
But you're a woman, aren't you?
那么
Sooo.
这些都是你的吗?
Are those yours?
没错 中央情报局颁的
Yeah, CIA.
我这么问的意思是我也有个勋章
I only ask because I also have a medal.
是总统颁的
From the President.
不错嘛
Yeah.
很好 这样事情就没那么复杂了 是吧?
Great, so it's not that complicated, right?
没有我的准许 谁也不能和汽车人一起共事
No one gets to work with the Autobots unless I approve it.
你在破坏我的指挥系统
You're breaking my chain of command.
好了 我们走
Come on, let's go.
你已经为他们尽了你最大的能力
You've done what you can for them.
恕我直言 年轻人
With all due respect, young man.
我很佩服你所做的
I appreciate what you did.
但你不是士兵
But you're not a soldier.
你是信使 一直都只是信使
You're a messenger, you've always been a messenger.
他是英雄
He's a hero.
大黄蜂 你去乘公务电梯 我们在那碰头
Bee, you take the freight elevator, I'll see you up there.
啊 真差劲
Ah, this blows.
- 那个长官阿姨把我们赶出来了  - 是啊
- That lady officially kicked us out.  - Yeah.
去他妈的证人保护计划
Witness protection program sucks.
没错 但有了大黄蜂...
Yeah, but we're a whole...
...和他的武器我们可安全多了
...lot safer with big yellow and his cannons.
那只狗可不保护了我们
That dog can't protect crap.
大黄蜂
Bee.
你睡不着吧
You couldn't sleep.
是啊 我也一样
Yeah, me too.
真不敢相信她管我叫信使
I don't believe she called me a messenger.
你相信吗? 我做了这么多 最终却只是个信使
Do you believe that? After everything I've done, I'm a messenger.
噢 甭提了 萨米 我们也很不爽
Oh, I believe it. I tell ya, Sammy, we feel the same way.
这星球的无礼现象真令人讨厌
The disrespect on this rock is criminal.
我们得做点什么
We should do something about it.
大黄蜂
Bee.
我想知道他们为什么要杀害人类
I need to know why they're killing humans.
我们打电话问专家吧
What say we call in the expert?
我的下位嘉宾 是一位敢于就我们的军事联盟
My next guest, is a former American intelligence operative
进行表态的...
who has dared to speak out...
...前美国情报局的特工
...regarding our alleged military alliance,
...许多人称我的盟军为...
...with what many describe...
...一群外星雇佣军
...as a group of extraterrestrial mercenaries.
他就是畅销书"代号英雄"的作者
He is the author of the best selling book, "Code-Name Hero".
有请我们的特工先生 西摩・西蒙斯
For our special agent, Seymour Simmons.
比尔 粉丝们 很高兴来到这里
Bill, big fan. Great to be here.
那么 特工西蒙斯
Now, agent Simmons.
这就是你想让我们相信的吧 在这场所谓的外星人内战中支持某一方...
You would have us believe that it is in our best centuries...
...也关乎着我们人类的利益?
...to formally take sides in this so called alien civil war?
没错 另一方早想把我们给活吃了 所以
Well, the other side wanted to spank us for breakfast, so.
不用纠结选择站在哪一方
I wouldn't exactly want to call it a toss up.
霸天虎们是坏的一方
These decepticons are lethal.
但民意调查显示...
But polls show half the world...
...人们觉得没有这些汽车人世界会更加安全
...would feel safer with the Autobots completely gone.
把他们赶出地球
Get them out of here.
这里不需要他们
We don't need them here.
和手榴弹一起睡觉我觉得会安全得多
I feel safer when I sleep with a hand grenade.
当然这不意味我总是对的
It doesn't mean I'm always right.
谢谢 事实是 我们得到了文件
Thank you. Here's a fact, we obtained documents that show you were
- 上面写着你是被情报局委员会开除的  - 查克 我正在做采访呢
- fired by the intelligence committee.  - Chuck, I'm doing the interview.
比尔 这是为了减少开支
Down sized. Bill, budget cuts.
- 出去  - ...据说你有严重的妄想症
- Chuck, out.  - ...report get severe delusional tendencies.
这是诽谤
This is ambush journalism.
你想知道关于外星人联盟的真相吗?
You want the truth about the alien alliance?
那就买我的书吧
Buy my book.
买我的书吧!
Buy my book!
趁早 伙计
Before it's to late, people.
你想跟我单挑吗比尔 你想让我发火吗?
You want to piss me, Bill, you want get naked?
来吧 采访结束了
I'm ready, interview is over.
- 你暴露了 你是个白痴  - 滚出我的家
- You sound like a pin-head agent.  - You get out of my house.
给你个忠告
And I got a suggestion for you.
结束了 懂?
It is over, understand?
控制情绪
Damage control.
- 小荷!  - 你们显然把西蒙斯先生激怒了
- Dutch!  - You have obviously upset Mr. Simmons.
你们有23秒可以离开这里
You have 23 seconds to leave the property.
我已经叫了警察
I have called the police.
你们这是自不量力
You are peasant people throwing rocks at a giant.
下一步有什么安排?
What's up next, what have we got?
中午在市中心进行签书活动
Book signing midtown at noon,
然后给探索周刊拍真人秀
then your pic reality show for discovery HM.
噢 还有 嗯... 嗯
Oh, and I had this, um... um.
威特维奇今天打了我五次电话了
The Witwicky who keeps calling me five times today.
那个小鬼 他想干什么?
The kid, what does he want?
我找你是因为霸天虎们...
I called because the decepticons...
...又回来了 我想知道为什么 而我需要你的帮助
...are back and I want to know why, and I need your help.
他们又回来了?
They're back?
呃 这是个赚钱的好门路
Well, that's good for business.
如果我说我知道一个...
What if I told you I know a 50...
...你不知道的50年前的外星秘密呢?
...year old alien secret that nobody ever told you?
别吊我味口
Do not tempt my addiction.
我已经金盆洗手了 小鬼
I have gone through withdrawal, kid.
小荷 这条线安全吗?
Dutch, is this line secure?
不安全
No.
别冒险
Don't take the risk.
我有钱了 干嘛还要做?
I'm rich, why should I?
我不能插手 决不
Do not relapse, I won't.
一定要意志坚定
Do not let the demons win.
线路安全
好了
Got.
是什么... 秘密?
What kind of... secret?
阿波罗 月球 外星人 掩饰...
Apollo, moon, aliens, cover-up...
...未来科技 暗杀行动 就是这些
...future tech, assassinations, that kind of stuff.
噢 阿波罗
Oh, Apollo.
小荷!
Dutch!
告诉威震天 开始舞蹈吧
Tell Megatron, let's tango.
这个星球是如此宏伟和宁静
So majestic and peaceful, this planet.
真不像塞伯坦最后的那些日子
Unlike the final days of Cybertron.
我很好奇到底会发生什么
I've wondered what might have been.
如果是你参加了最后决战
If you had fought the final battle.
而不是我
Instead of me.
不要追悼过去 年轻的战士
Never morn the past, young warrior.
多亏了你 我们的种族延续了下来
Thanks to you, our race survives.
你才是我们的首领 御天敌
You were our leader, Sentinel.
重新引领我们 这是你的权利
It is your right to lead us again.
在一个我不了解的世界
In a world I do not know.
我再也不是你的老师了 擎天柱
I am no longer your teacher, Optimus.
你是我的老师
You are mine.
我们得解决这个麻烦
We've got to break this case down.
这是一起宇航员连环失事事件
What we have here is an astronaut epidemic.
失踪 死亡 车祸
M.I.A., dead, died in a car accident,
被杀 抢救失败
killed, D.O.A., car death.
好像这些宇航员命硬
It's like these guys can't drive.
能开飞船到外太空去
They can fly into outer space.
但他们竟然不会开车
But they can't drive a car.
收到你的信息了 威特维奇
Procured your information, Witwicky.
谢谢 布鲁斯
Thank you, Bruce.
不
Noo.
让我见识见识汽车人 就一次
You let me see one of them, one time.
- 快点  - 很快
- Quick.  - Very.
这是他们的月球探测命令
Here's their reconnaissance order.
上面说是美国宇航局2009年发布的
It say's NASA launched in 2009.
瞧 恢复数据表明老王可能把密码弄乱了
See, forensics show Wang may have messed with the code
以阻止其给月球远端绘图
preventing it from mapping the far side of the moon
也就是阴暗面
which is also the dark side.
真他妈带劲儿
Freaking awesome.
他们策反了一些人类 威胁他们
They pay for trade us, intimidate us.
...为他们卖命
...coerce us to do their dirty work.
那一旦他们成功了呢?
And once they're done?
咔嚓
Dushhhh.
就杀人灭口
The double tap cerebellum.
这么说他帮霸天虎们做事
So he was working for the Decepticons.
我觉得霸天虎不是
I don't think this is about the Decepticons.
在寻找月球上的某种东西
looking for something on the moon.
我觉得他们是想藏什么东西
I think it's about something they wanted to hide.
来爸爸这儿
Come to daddy.
听话 坐下
Come on, fall down.
你小时候吃过很多廉价薯片吗?
Did you eat a lot of paint chips when you were a kid?
怪人一个
The freak.
啊 是很喜欢
Hah, like it.
我来教教你...
I'll teach you...
长官
Sir.
这里正开着十分高级别的外星人研讨会
Having a pretty high level alien Intel confab here.
我想你应该不能进来吧
That I don't think you're cleared for.
- 小跟班  - 是啊 你说对了
- Errand boy.  - Yeah, you're right.
- 真是个坏脾气的机器人  - 请便 先生
- It's a bitchin' robot.  - I think it's time to go, Bruce, okay?
谢谢你让我进来参观
Thank you so much for this.
该走了 布鲁斯
Better go, Bruce.
嘿 我在那抽烟
Hey, I'm smokin' over here.
至于那些失踪的俄罗斯宇航员
Now with the missing Russian cosmonauts.
其实是苏联当时取消了登月计划
Turns out the soviets cancelled a manned mission to the moon.
1972年的登月计划
The moon, in 1972
200名宇航员继而躲进了美国
when 2 of cosmonauts went into hiding in America.
而我刚刚找到了他们 哈哈
And I just found them, aaaah.
你真是个天才 Brains
You're a genius, Brains.
噢 你真行 大黄蜂
Oh, that was smooth, Bumble Bee.
刚才真不错
Missed it by that much.
嗨
Hi.
有人能告诉我这发生什么了吗?
Would somebody tell me what the hell's going on?
你是谁?
Who are you?
- 你是谁?  - 我是谁?
- Who are you?  - Who am I?
他是谁? 小荷 搜她的身
Who is that? Dutch, frisk her.
- 没问题  - 嘿 别
- Certainly.  - Here, no.
小荷 呃...
Dutch, um...
别碰我
Don't touch me.
- 我不打算...  - 怎么解释萨姆?
- I'm not going to...  - Sam?
宝贝儿
Angel.
呃 我在工作
Uh, I was working.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry about this.
真好 我们无家可归了
Great, we're homeless.
她住在这里?
She lives here?
你本来有机会搜她身的
You had your chance to frisk her.
我有女朋友了
I have a girl friend.
是吗 她叫什么?
Really, what's her name?
叫伊迪儿
Innn... dia.
我们要去迪兰的派对的 还记得吗?
We're suppose to be at Dylan's party, remember?
当然记得 但你知道 我的伙计们
I do remember, but you know, my friends,
...他们需要我 我现在得待在这里
...they need me. I have to be here right now.
怎么 汽车人和...
And what, the Autobots and the...
...军队自己搞不定是吧
...military they can't handle this on their own.
你知道为什么我喜欢你的英雄故事吗 萨姆?
You know what I liked about your war stories, Sam?
因为它们只是故事
It's that they were stories.
它们只存在于过去
They were in the past.
听着 我知道你在想着你的哥哥
Look, I know you're thinking about your brother.
还有 你也在想着你的家人
Okay, and you're thinking about your family.
但这和你哥哥的情况不一样
And it's not that situation.
- 不一样?  - 对
- No?  - No.
为什么不一样?
Why not?
对我来说都一样 萨姆
Why isn't it, Sam?
你觉得我们是希望拥有他的奖章 还是他还在我们身边?
You think we'd rather has his medals, or we'd rather have him?
我知道 我明白了
I hear you, I get it.
你要把我的兔宝宝带哪儿去 别走
Where are you taking my bunny, stop.
就等一下
Just stop for a second.
你觉得我晚上睡得安稳?
You think I could sleep last night?
那种感觉一直冲击我 不 萨姆就是喜欢冒险
I mean it hit me. No, Sam want's the big danger.
不危险他自己都找不着北了
He doesn't know who he is without it.
我只是希望自己不那么平庸
I just wanna matter.
对我来说 你一点也不平庸
You matter to me.
我知道你担心我 我真的知道
I know you're worried, I know you're worried.
但我向你保证 我可以解决这事
But I promise you I can, I can handle this.
你真可以 你保证?
Can you, you can promise it?
我保证
I promise.
萨姆 我不想打击你 但我知道结果会怎样
Sam, I don't want to loose you, and I know where this leads.
我还没心理准备
I'm not ready for this.
你和我一起来吧?
Are you coming with me?
我不能这么做
I can't.
好
Okay.
这是能带来好运的兔子腿
Here's your foot.
勇者总是孤独
A warrior's path is a solitary one.
见鬼 她怎么买得起那么好的车
How the hell does she afford that car?
- 她老板买给她的  - 该死的有钱人
- Her boss.  - Rich bastards.
以前我看他们不爽
I used to hate them.
不过现在嘛...
But now it's...
...为了找那两个苏联宇航员 麻烦跑到混混中去
...Going to a gang on a hunt for two Russian Cosmonauts.
迈巴赫豪华轿车就是大不一样 对吧?
Nothing like driving in a Maybach, huh?
德国人就是会造车 我告诉你
Germans know how to make cars, let me tell ya.
我雇的荷兰人 前国家安全局特工
My Dutch man. Former NSA,
网络信息侦查高手
Cyber sleuth extraordinaire.
查出他们就在这儿
Tracked them down, here.
看来这些宇航员想躲起来 什么原因呢?
So these cosmonauts wanted to hide. Why?
没错 我找到匹配目标
Bingo, I got a match.
你比德国牧羊犬还厉害 小荷
You're a German Shepard, Dutch.
说到俄国人...
The thing about Russians is...
...和他们谈不出什么来的
...they never like to talk.
对付他们得用点国际通用语
It's going to take a little of the international language.
- Dos vedanya(俄语)  - 那是再见的意思
- Dos vedanya.  - That means goodbye.
谁引发了革命?
Who's to get revolution.
一个很有名的人 但我不知道是谁
A famous, I have no idea.
小荷
Dutch.
给我几句狠话吓吓他们
Give me something tough.
- 巴雷什尼科夫  - 我们会说英语
- Baryshnikov.  - We do speak English.
小荷 你真菜
Dutch, you suck.
这是西里尔语 全是生僻词
It's a Cyrillic, alphabet.
就像你计算机上那些从没用过的按钮一样
It's like all the buttons you never push on a calculator.
我不菜
I don't suck.
我是西摩・西蒙斯特工 观测航天飞行活动 此前从事监测外星物体工作
Agent Seymour Simmons, CETI. Formerly Seta.
我们知道你的来历
We know who you are.
宇航员小妞
Cosmonaut chicks.
你想怎样?
So what?
你们当初本该进发到月球的暗面 但是...
You were suppose to travel to the Dark side of the moon, then....
突然计划取消了
It all got shut down.
我想知道的是
The question is.
为什么
Why?
我的小孩能在这吸烟吗?
Can my child smoke in here?
好啊 来啊 好啊!
Okay, all right. Okay!
- 来啊 打我啊  - 这位小甜心是谁啊?
- Yeah, shoot me.  - Who was this delish, huh?
我在我的国家就是个司机 你是吗?
I'm only the driver in my country are you?
你真美
You are beautiful.
以前从没人和你说过你真美吗?
Has anyone told you, you're beautiful?
因为她是个美女
'Cause she's a beautiful woman.
小荷 别乱来
Dutch, back in the cage.
管好你小弟 麻烦你管好你小弟
Control your boy, please control your boy.
小荷 住手!
Dutch, stop!
对不起 职业病犯了
I'm so sorry. That is the old me.
好 我们大家都冷静点
Okay, let's everybody just calm down.
缓解气氛 放下枪 都放轻松
Let's lower the heat, lower the guns. Just relax.
第二次冷战结束了
World War 2 is over.
你即将见到的是苏联最大的秘密之一
You're about to see one of the biggest soviet secrets.
的确是美国先把人类送上月球的
America first to send men to the moon.
但苏联航天局则是最早把摄像机送上去的
But U.S.S.R. First to send camera.
在1969年 我们的三号月球探测器
In 1959 our Lunar 3.
拍了月球阴暗面的照片
take picture of the Dark, the shadow side.
什么都没看见
See's nothing.
- 但到1963年四号探测器拍到了...  - 奇怪的岩石
- But in 1963 Lunar 4 sees...  - ...strange rocks.
- 对  - 围绕着飞船
- Yeah.  - Around the ship.
有数百个
Hundreds of them.
给他们看看照片
Here, show picture.
上面还有 拖拽的痕迹
With some, drag marks.
这我见过 这些不是普通石头
I've seen these, these aren't rocks.
是能量柱
These are pillars.
外星能量柱 用于搭建太空桥
Alien pillars for a space bridge.
我们能认出来 是因为汽车人手里也有五根
We know about them because the Autobots have five of these.
霸天虎肯定...
The decepticons must have...
...在阿波罗11号登月之前就占领了太空船
...raided the ship before Apollo 11 ever got there.
抢走能量柱 并藏了起来
Took the pillars and hid them.
这就怪了 既然飞船已经在霸天虎手里
Well that doesn't make sense. The Decepticons have the ship.
他们本该拿到所有能量柱
They have all those pillars.
那怎么会留下几根...
Why would they leave several...
...只有御天敌会用能量柱?
...of these if he's the only one that can use them?
莫非...
Unless...
御天敌也是他们想要得到的
He's the one thing they still need.
我们得赶快找到御天敌
We got to meet up with Sentinel.
去和他会合 保证他的安全
Rendezvous with him, and keep him safe.
米樱 我刚刚找到御天敌 擎天柱十分钟后到
Mearing, I just picked up Sentinel, Optimus is 10 minutes behind.
我们正高速赶来
We're coming in fast, now.
威特维奇先生 我想我对你讲的够明白了
Mr. Witwicky I thought I made it clear to you,
我不希望你再打电话
that I did not want you calling this phone.
听着 整件事从一开始就是个圈套
Listen, the whole thing has been a set up since the beginning.
霸天虎想让擎天柱去找到御天敌
Decepticons wanted Optimus to find Sentinel,
因为只有擎天柱能让他复活
because only Optimus could revive him.
但我们有太空桥
But we have the space bridge.
米樱 你有五个能量柱
Mearing, you have five pillars.
我刚刚知道霸天虎有数百根
I just learned that they have hundreds.
你这样做正中他们下怀
You're doing exactly what they wanted you to do.
我该怎么跟你说呢
What do I need to say to you.
霸天虎就是冲着御天敌来的
The Decepticons are coming for Sentinel Prime.
出发去鹰巢
We're going to NEST.
外星能量警报
We have an Energon alert.
追踪目标
Currently tracking.
三辆黑色越野车
Three black suburban.
大黄蜂 你护送御天敌离开这 加大油门!
B, you gotta get Sentinel out of here, you got to floor it.
哦 老天爷 哦 我居然没事
Oh man, oh I'm fine.
小心 小心
Watch out, watch out.
抓到你了
Gotcha.
开枪打他 开枪打他!
Shoot him, shoot him!
大黄蜂 打它
Shoot him, B.
大黄蜂 你该行动了 快点 再快点 大黄蜂 快!
B, you gotta move. Faster, faster B, go!
我完了
Wipeout.
快点 回鹰巢
Come on, back to NEST.
恐龙 我来对付他
Dino, I got him.
有麻烦了吗?
Is there a problem?
哇噢 我们像西部片里一样决斗呢
Whoa, little Mexican stand-off we got here.
放下枪
Weapons down.
我们会让你们有尊严地离开
And we'll let you escape with your dignity.
放下枪
Drop them.
非常好
That's good.
铁皮 小心
Ironhide, watch out.
铁皮 接着
Ironhide, catch.
小心后面
Behind you.
霸天虎这些个败类
Decepticon punk.
解散
Class dismissed.
- 进去 快进去  - 进去
- Inside, let's go.  - Move.
快点 别磨蹭
Quick, move it.
- 雷尼克斯  - 走 走 走 走
- Lennox.  - Go, go, go, go.
到处都是霸天虎
We got decepticons everywhere.
我安排弟兄们去找他们了
I got my whole team deployed looking for them.
铁皮!
Ironhide!
保护好御天敌 让他进去
Protect Sentinel, get him locked up inside.
包在我身上
Consider it done.
你要看好他 因为他是整个事的关键
You gotta guard him, because he's the key to the whole thing.
我的确是关键
Indeed I am.
我的汽车人兄弟们 你们要知道
What you must realized, my Autobot brothers.
我们从来就没有获胜的希望
Is we were never going to win the war.
为了保住我们的星球
For the sake of our planets survival.
我不得不和威震天
A deal had to be made.
做一个交易
With Megatron.
退后!
Get back!
你这是干什么?
What have you done?
我在此宣布解除你的使命
I hereby discharge you from duty.
- 大黄蜂!  - 退后
- B!  - Get back.
所有的弟兄全部撤回基地
Bring all the NEST forces back to the base.
快点 动起来
Come on, move.
把他们弄进来 让他们躺那 我们人手不够
Get them in, get them here. We don't have enough men.
不要和御天敌直接交锋
Do not engage Sentinel.
从后门进入
Just go to the back gate.
局长 趴下
Director, down.
拖他们走 拖他们走
Let's slide, let's slide
走 跟着我
Go, follow me.
开火
Start firing.
- 等等 别进去  - 走开
- Wait don't.  - Get out.
嘿 御天敌
Hey, Sentinel.
这是怎么回事?
What is going on?
你在做什么?
What do you think you're doing?
我是个超级领袖
I am a Prime.
你没资格冲我发号施令
I do not take orders from you.
米樱局长 快来 我们打不过他的 走吧
Director Mearing come on. We can't fight him, let's go.
- 我们得走了  - 现在
- We have to go.  - Now.
把我的还给我
Return what belongs to me.
上帝啊
Oh, my god.
所有人都出去 所有人都出去
Everybody out, everybody out.
都给我冷静
Everybody stay calm.
你看看 擎天柱
Yeah take a look, Optimus.
都怪你
This is all on you.
御天敌突袭仓库
The Sentinel hit the vault.
把能量柱都拿走了
Took the pillars.
走 我们走
Come on, let's go.
好 通知101空降师
All right, notify the 101st airborne.
一定要把他拿下
We need to hunt this thing down.
卡莉啊
Carly.
小心烫
Hot from a little camp fire.
篝火烤出的曲奇饼
Smores.
这样多好 原生态食物啊
Isn't this great, we are really living off the land.
妈 爸 你们有看见卡莉回家吗?
Ma, Dad. Have you guys seen Carly come home yet?
不好意思 你进来前能敲门吗?
Excuse me, can you knock please.
这可是我们的卧室
This is our bedroom.
她怎么会不在家呢?
Why wouldn't she be at home?
我们吵架了 然后...
We had a fight, and...
我们说不定要分手了 或者是 暂时分开一段
We might have broken up, or be on a break.
我也不清楚
I don't really know.
- 什么!?... 不  - 我现在没空说这些
- What!?... Noo.  - Look, I can't talk about it.
- 你逗我玩吧  - 我...
- You gotta be kidding me.  - I...
...现在没空说细节 妈 我要找到她
...can't go into details now, Mom. I have to find her.
萨姆 我们要开个家庭会议
Sam, we're having a family meeting.
家庭会议
Family meeting.
你可能不知道 但...
You may not know this. But your...
...你爸和我不是都像现在这么高兴的
...father and I were not always this perfectly happy.
告诉你 在结婚后曾经有段时间 我在想
You know there was a time in our marriage when I thought,
"这样下去没结果的"
"This is not going to work out."
- 你能快点吗  - 我只是希望你...
- Can you please hurry up.  - I'm just hope you ...
- ...你能明白你...  - 我不敢
- ...just understand that you...  - She's damaging me.
...和一个世界级美女分手
...break up with one world class high.
- 不 别说了 别说了 别说了  - 我就要说
- No, stop, stop, okay.  - Yeah.
她甩了我 我有更重要的事
She dumped me, I moved to something better.
就是这样 我现在更开心了
That's it, I'm a happier person.
这不如你想象的美好...
It's not going to be as beautiful...
- 失去她 你怎么失去她的?  - 帮帮我
- Lose her, why did you lose her?  - Help me.
- 他们吵架了  - 我们有争执
- They had an argument.  - We had a fight.
好吧 但你不可能再遇到第三个了
Okay, but you're not going to get a third one.
我是说除非你有...
I mean unless you have like a big...
什么乱七八糟的 妈!
What the, mom!
妈 妈  别说了
Mom, mom, don't want to talk about it.
我觉得你就是不懂
I mean you just don't know.
- 我只是不想说了  - 你要看看这本书
- Just don't want to talk.  - You need a book.
错都在你
You'll always wrong.
- 要学着习惯  - 对 你一定要认真读这本书
- Get used to it. -Okay, this you gotta read this.
女人总是对的 这本书可是...
She comes first, there's some killer...
- ...金玉良言啊  - 不 不 不
- ...shit in here.  - No, No, No.
- 啊 又来了  - 不 不
- Ah, let's get this.  - No, no.
- 不 不  - 坐下  坐下!
- No, no.  - Sit down. Sit down!
附和我
Back me up.
老婆高兴 生活就美好
Happy wife, happy life.
- 对  - 老婆不高兴...
- Yeah.  - unhappy wife...
余生凄凉痛苦如墓碑...
Stone cold misery for the rest of your...
- 打住  - 我说的没错啊
- Stop.  - It's true.
我说了这么多
All I'm saying is.
你到底喜欢她吗?
Do you love this girl?
她是我此生挚爱
She's the one.
那你就去找她
Then you gotta go get her.
其实 当我和你爸出现感情危机的时候
I mean, your dad and I, when we had troubles.
你老爸为了找我跑遍了天涯海角
He moved heaven and earth to find me.
对吧 你当时是怎么说那句话的
Would he, say what you said.
快说呀
Say it.
我会陪你到天荒地老
I would follow you to the end of time.
- 觉得蛋疼么?  - 不
- Does that suck or what?  - No.
跟演偶像剧一样
Bad syfy dope.
我要你们离开这里 有多远走多远
I want you guys to get as far away from here as you can.
明白没?
You understand?
我爱你们
I love you.
哦 我的主人
Oh, my master.
这真是一个绝妙的计划
Such a brilliant scheme.
所以说 当初御天敌离开塞伯坦的时候...
So, when Sentinel left Cybertron...
...就已经打算背叛汽车人了
...it was to defect.
他本应该和在我地球会合的
He was meant to rendezvous with me here on Earth,
只是没想到我们半途失手
before fate waylaid us both.
复活他的唯一方法
The only way to revive him,
...就是擎天柱和他的能源矩阵
...we needed Prime and his matrix.
完美的计划
Excellent strategy.
那么他现在站在你这边了 主人
So he is now your partner, master.
我就赢在了他身上
He is my greatest triumph.
太霸气了
So impressive.
准备传送
Commencing transport.
不要! 别这样 停下 御天敌!
Stop! No, no, no Sentinel!
原谅我吧
Forgive me.
好戏要开场了
Here we are.
战个痛快
Fight us now.
汽车人 撤退
Autobots, retreat.
御天敌 这是为什么?
Why Sentinel, why?
为了塞伯坦
For Cybertron.
为了我们的家园
For our home.
要重建被战争摧毁的家园
What war destroyed, we can rebuild.
只有与霸天虎合作
But only if we join with the Decepticons.
不 还有别的办法
No, it's not the only way.
这才是我们的家
This is our home.
我们必须保护人类
We must defend the humans.
你太糊涂了 擎天柱
So lost you are, Optimus.
在塞伯坦我们曾是神明
On Cybertron we were Gods.
而在这里却被当成机器
And here they call us machines.
要让这些人类臣服于我们
Let the humans serve us.
否则便毁灭之
Or perish.
你该庆幸我没有杀你
You're lucky I didn't kill you.
很快 你会明白的
In time, you'll see.
还没有结束
It's not over.
要我是他的话
And if I were him,
...我一秒都不会让你离开我的视线
...I wouldn't let you out of my sight for one second.
真有意思 来这儿的路上我还在想
It's funny I was just thinking on the way over here,
迪兰的有些建议确实挺适用
I really could use some advice from Dylan.
- 结果他还真在这 能跟你说几句?  - 欢迎
- And there he is. Can I speak to you?  - Welcome.
请坐 喝两杯
Please sit down, have a drink.
我跟你讲 我不用你给酒喝
You know what, I don't need a drink.
也不用你给车 给工作
Or a car, or a job.
我只想跟我女朋友单独说几句话
I just need to speak to my girlfriend alone.
行吗 不合适先生?
Is that okay with you, Mr. Inappropriate?
不好意思 失陪
Excuse me.
- 发生什么了?  - 出去告诉你
- What's going on?  - I'll tell you outside.
我觉得我肯定能帮你 萨姆
I really think I can help you, Sam.
我记得和我父亲的一次谈话 关于两难的选择
I remember a talk I had with my dad once, about tough choices.
现在不是时候 改天我再抽时间聊这些
Now's not the time, I'll set something up, though.
那时候我父亲的公司还在负责
'Cause that was way back when my dad's firm was in charge
美航局的预算审查和会计工作
of budget review and accounting for NASA.
他教会我的是...
You see the thing that he taught me was...
...如果这是一场不属于你的战争
...When it's not your war,
你就加入能获胜的一方
you join the side that's going to win.
交给上面 还是我来解决?
Too direct, or was it just me?
悉随尊便
Certainly not you, sir.
还想跑
You're mine.
- 快来人 快帮帮忙  - 萨姆 我出不去了
- Get help. Someone get help.  - Sam, I can't get out.
- 晚安  - 晚安迪兰先生
- Goodnight  - Goodnight Mr. Dylan.
萨姆 救救我
Sam, get me out of here.
来人啊
Help.
救命
Get help.
他还嫩 会学着上道的
He's young, he will learn.
- 救命  - 晚安
- Get me out.  - Goodnight.
有趣的晚上
This was a fun night.
你真的认为...
You really think you're the...
...第一个跟外星生物有接触的人是你?
...first man ever asked to join a noble alien cause?
你到底是谁?
Who are you?
知道为什么我们...
You know why we've not...
...在1972年以后就没再登过月吗?
...been back to the moon since 1972?
因为它们俩
Because these two.
他们找上我老爸
They came to my dad and
让他在账目上做点小动作
they told him to do some creative accounting.
把再次登月的预算变成天价
Make it way to expensive to ever go back.
于是他们那帮人 叫停了...
So he and others, shut...
...美俄宇宙空间项目
...down the American and Russian space programs.
后来他们就成了我们的委托人
And they've been our clients ever since.
你协助他们入侵地球?
You helped to kill people?
你觉得他们会给你选择的余地?
You think they give you a choice?
其实我本人并没有亲自参与进去
Besides, it's not like I personally participated.
我只是个中间人
I am a liaison.
信使而已
I liaise.
地球被恶意收购了 萨姆
It's hostile take over time, Sam.
吖萨姆!
Sam!
放开她!
Let her go.
吖萨姆!
Sam.
我已经关注你好几年了 萨姆
I've had my eye on you for years, Sam.
你就是我看中...
You're the one spy I've never been...
...能当汽车人身边的间谍的最佳人选
...able to provide as the one close to the Autobots.
萨姆 别让他得逞!
Sam, don't do what he wants.
他会听我的
Yes he will.
每个人都一样
They all do.
机灵点儿 听到了吗
You should be smarter. You understand me.
你一眨眼的时间
The time it takes you to blink,
她就会死 就连我也一样
they will do it to her, and they will do it to me.
所以你最好放尊重点
So you show a little respect.
因为我他喵的在给你机会
When someone offers you a job.
手伸出来
Wrist.
我要你去跟踪擎天柱
You are to track down, Optimus Prime.
因为你是他唯一信任的地球人
Because you're the one human he trusts.
然后从他嘴里面问出
You will ask one question.
他打算如何反击?
How does he intend to fight back?
策略 战术 一切的一切
Strategies, tactics, everything.
这下肯定咬得爽
Has a nasty little bite, doesn't it.
这个小东西很高端
It's very high tech.
能让我们见你...
It lets us see...
...所见 闻你所闻
...what you see, hear what you hear.
并且已经侵入了你的神经系统
And it attacks your nervous system.
所以你最好别想动什么歪脑筋
So if you so much as try and signal.
有句话 萨姆
I know what to tell you, Sam.
不同的关系带来不同的后果
Relationships have consequences.
我因为我父亲而站在这里
I am here because my father,
她则因为你受尽折磨
she is here because of you.
不要! 停 停... 停
Stop! Stop, stop... stop.
声波 差不多了
Soundwave, if you please.
萨姆啊
Sam.
只要你完成任务
Do your job.
她就会平安无事 我保证
She'll be safe. I give you my word.
我一定会杀了你
I'll kill you.
我也保证
You have my word.
进入1级防卫状态
Combatant commands are now at Defcon 1.
将近200名霸天虎隐藏在各处
Approximately 200 Decepticons are in hiding.
能源探测器已经启动...
Energon detectors have been...
...南美 中国 全球各地都探测到异动
...triggered as far away as South America and China.
联合国刚刚收到一份加密音频文件
The U.N. just received an encrypted audio file.
据说是汽车人的领袖发来的
They say it's from the leaders of the Autobots.
地球的守护者们
Defenders of Earth.
我们是为地球上的资源而来
We have come for your natural resources.
目的是重建我们破碎的家园
To rebuild our damaged planet.
传送完我们需要的一切之后
When we have transported all we needed.
我们将会和平地离开这个星球
We will leave your world in peace.
和平的条件是
For such peace to exist.
你们必须立刻驱逐之前窝藏的所有汽车人
You must immediately exile the Autobot rebels you have harbored.
没有条件可谈
Non negotiable.
驱逐那帮汽车人
Renounce the rebels.
等待你们的答复
We await your reply.
我们会在路上告诉你大致情况
We'll debrief you in transit.
我实在没看出来我能帮上什么忙
Yeah I really don't see how I can be of any help.
你们都这么忙
I mean you guys seem pretty busy.
我想我们可以改天再会面
We can just do this another time, I think.
我的确是太低估你了
I have underestimated you at every turn.
你... 呃... 说什么?
You... Ha... what?
你警告过我们说他们在利用人类
You warned us that they were using humans.
并且知道御天敌才是关键
And you knew that Sentinel was the key.
老大
Director.
不是吧 我算什么? 嘿 你才是专家
Oh, who am I? Hey, you're the expert.
我只是个会移动的泄密器
I'm just a walking security risk.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
没事
Yes.
- 肯定有事 你都出汗了  - 不 我很好
- No you're not, you're sweating.  - No, I'm fine.
真没事 我出汗是紧张了
I'm fine. I'm sweating because I'm nervous.
我是在为此紧张...
I'm nervous because you...
...你为了这么重大的事情把我叫来
...got me in here for this information, okay.
我天天泡微博 在博客发布一切消息
I'm a twitter junkie, I blog everything,
我可保守不了秘密
I can't keep secrets.
- 噢 你不敢泄密的  - 我说的都是真的
- Oh you wouldn't dare.  - That's the truth, I'm telling you.
你敢泄露一个字试试
You wouldn't dare.
长官 15号线有您的电话
Director I got a call for you at 15.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
没事 你在干什么?
Nothing, what are you doing?
离我远点
Get away from me.
今天国会宣布了数项重大举措
It's been a remarkable series of events today at the Capitol.
不久前 国会通过了...
Just moments ago legislation was...
...将汽车人驱逐出境的法案
...passed to exile the Autobots from American shores.
而他们与美国的军事同盟也正式宣告结束
The U.S. Military alliance with them is officially over.
- 白宫发言人及当局领导...  - 说
- The words of the house and the...  - Yeah.
对今天的决议发表了看法
Authority leaders responds to today's resolution.
- 什么?  - 我们不应自主地邀请...
- What?  - We cannot in good conscious invite...
他们不能这样 你得去阻止他们
They can't do this, you gotta tell them they can't do that.
好了 上头发话了 该走了 伙计们!
Okay, it's official, it's a go people!
汽车人是我们的盟友
These are our allies.
他们曾保护我们 与我们并肩作战
The Autobot's fought for us, they fought with us.
我们现在下场如何?
And where are we now?
我们面临敌人的侵略
Facing an enemy invasion.
这是一支有办法无限增长的敌军
With an enemy that has the means to deploy countless more.
如果你还掌握更多的情报?
If there's more you know?
比如敌人的意图或动向
Anything at all about the enemies intentions.
现在最好全说出来
Now's the time to tell.
汽车人没有办法离开地球
Autobots have no way of leaving this planet.
那你就大错特错了
That is where you're wrong.
它叫苍耳号
Its name is the Xanthium.
当初第二波汽车人就是乘它来的
It bought the second wave of Autobots.
一直以来都是美国航天局在保护并研究它
And it's been under NASA's care and study ever since.
我们把它连接在一架退役的航天飞机上
We've linked it with a decommissioned shuttle,
并在他们离开之前对其保持军事监控
to maintain military control until they're gone.
那破烂玩意儿
Gonna be 10,000 pounds of torque
至少需要10,000磅的扭力... 与我无关
on this cheaper Cheep... Oh, not my thing.
这样会耽误进度的
You damage this delays all me mates.
他们是清障车
That's your wreckers.
苍耳号由他们负责
They take care of the Xanthium.
原则上我们不让他们离开基地
We don't let them off the base much,
因为他们实在是两个白痴
because they're assholes.
你该拉着那个 你这个傻瓜
You gotta pull that you Nancy wanker.
这样的力矩会把它们弄坏的
It's torqued to kill them.
冷静点
Calm down.
- 埃普斯  - 你居然在这 你太不可理喻了
- Epps.  - You are ridiculous, that's you.
你好 伙计
Hello, man.
- 你在这干嘛呀  - 我已经从空军退役了
- What are you doing here  - I'm retired from the air force.
能放开我的手吗?
Can you let my hand go?
你刚刚怎么了?
What the hell was that?
后来我就做咨询工作 也帮他们做做掩护
I went on to just consult and run interference for them.
不用再打仗...
No more combat...
...不用再给外星人当靶子
...or alien shooting at my ass.
这是我梦寐以求的工作
I got a dream job.
要赶走所有汽车人
Kicking the Autobots out.
难以置信 不是吗?
Do you believe this is happening?
你觉得他们能去哪儿?
Where do you think is taking them?
除了地球都有可能
Any planet but here.
我有话要跟这里的负责人说
I want to talk to whoever's in charge here.
原来是夏洛特・米樱啊
Charlotte Mearing.
西蒙斯探员
Agent Simmons
应该是西蒙斯前探员
Former Agent Simmons, so.
看来你没死在华盛顿
I see you survived Washington.
华盛顿 埃及 心碎往事
Washington, Egypt, heartbreak.
我都熬过来了 以后也能熬过去
I survived, I will survive.
他们将每个人都牵扯进来了 孩子
They're bringing everybody in, kid.
所有情报都开诚公布
Putting all the Intel on the table.
如果你觉得扔掉9只汽车人
And if you think that putting 9 Autobots,
能解决现在面临的情况...
is going to solve a damn thing...
这不是我能左右的
It's out of my hands.
你升官发财了是吧?
Moving up in the world, huh?
你的翘臀真是太养眼了
Your booty looks excellent.
你要是敢跟任何人...
You ever say word to anyone...
...说起那晚在匡提科的事
...about what happened that night in Quantico.
我就把你的心整个挖出来
I'll cut your heart out.
你早就这么做了
You already did.
萨米 听我说
Sammy, listen to me.
别让他们赶我们走
Don't let them exile us.
别让他们带走我们 萨姆
Don't let them take us, Sam.
这是霸天虎的陷阱
It's a Decepticon trap.
氮气设备检查完毕 我们准备出发了
Checked the nitrogen, we're booting out of here.
擎天柱
Optimus.
你们的领导说得对
What your leaders say is true.
这全都是我的错
This was all my fault.
是我告诉他们该相信谁
I told them whom to trust.
我真是大错特错
I was so wrong.
你没有错
It doesn't make your fault,
这反而让你更像人类了
it makes you human for a change.
要记住
Remember this.
你也许不再对我们有信心
You may loose your faith in us.
但是永远都要相信自己
But never in yourselves.
我想知道你要怎样反击
I need to know how you're going to fight back.
我知道你有计划
I know there's a strategy.
我知道你会带着援军回来
I know you're coming back with reinforcements.
你一定有办法
Something, I know there's a plan.
你可以告诉我 我不会告诉任何人
You can tell me, no other human will ever know.
我没有计划
There is no plan.
我们全都听他们的
We just do what they want,
还怎么面对自己呢?
how are we going to live with ourselves?
你是我的朋友 萨姆
You are my friend, Sam.
你永远都是
You always will be.
但是你们的领导做了决定
But your leaders have spoken.
从现在开始
From here.
你必须自己战斗了
The fight will be your own.
长话短说
Make it short.
我们要出发了
We're loading up.
好吧 动作快点!
All right, hustle up!
我们会尽我们所能
When we do whatever we can.
就像以前那样
make it like it was.
你永远都是我的朋友
You will always be, my friend.
萨姆啊
Sam.
我该走了
I gotta be going on.
多年以后 他们会问我们
Years from now, they're gonna ask us.
霸天虎占领地球时 你们在哪?
Where were you when they took over the planet?
我们会回答说
We're gonna say.
我们只是冷眼旁观
We just stood by and watched.
早上6:30
你真应该视此为合作关系
You should really look at this as a partnership.
如果你想书写历史...
You have to stand on the side of progress...
...就必须站在代表进步的一方
...if you want to be a part of history.
倒计时... 五 四 三 二 一 零
Go launch in... 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 0.
你成功了
The word is, you got it.
我想要的都能得到 萨姆
I always get what I want, Sam.
我们只是还要确认一下
We just needed to be sure.
确认什么?
Sure of what?
确认他们将放弃抵抗 直接离开
That they would go without a fight.
- 再说一遍?  - 发现不明飞行物
- Say again?  - Detecting a foreign object.
从现在开始 我们都为霸天虎效力
We all work for the Decepticons now.
芝加哥 伊利诺斯
帮帮忙 我需要追踪一个电话
I need your help to track a phone call.
电话那边是个男人 他是霸天虎的人
It's a man on this phone, he's the head of the human operation.
他把卡莉抓做人质了
And he's holding Carly hostage.
坐下 不许动
Sit down, don't move.
我看见他就要开过来了
I'm watching him drive up right now.
电话是在路上打的
The call was placed in-route.
我马上能进入手机的摄像头
I'm hacking into the phone's camera right now.
看到了 这是摄像头的实时画面
There that is, that's a live stream from the camera.
我马上能三角定位出这个地方
Someplace, hold on I can triangulate this.
好了 是芝加哥的基站
Okay, it's Chicago cell site.
这儿 我查到了
There, I got it.
在芝加哥的川普大厦 较矮那栋的楼顶
Trump tower, Chicago, lower penthouse.
我们出发
We're on.
- 我要去  - 你确定
- I'm going.  - You're sure.
感谢您一直尽力帮助我...
She is out there without any help...
我15小时之内能赶到那儿
I can be there in 15 hours.
我和你一起去
You're not going alone.
那儿还有些我在鹰巢部队的朋友
Still got my NEST friends out there.
我们把他们召集起来
We'll round them up,
找到你的女朋友 抓住这家伙
find your girlfriend and bring this guy in.
你为什么帮我?
Why are you helping me?
因为那混蛋也杀了我的朋友
'Cause that asshole killed my friends, too.
他们说为了重建自己的星球
They said they were here for our resources.
他们需要我们的资源
To rebuild their planet.
没错 其实只要一种特点资源
Yes, really one resource in particular.
我们星球独有的
One unique to our planet.
人类
Us.
你很聪明
You're very smart.
他们没有奴隶 就不能重建家园
You see they can't rebuild without a slave labor force.
宇宙中有哪个星球能有60亿工人呢?
How many rocks up there in the universe offer 6 billion workers?
你说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
我们无法运输那么多人
We can't transport people.
他们不是要把人运走
They're not shipping people.
而是要把星球运到这儿来
They're shipping their planet here.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
御天敌怎么会在这儿?
What's Sentinel doing here?
看
Watch.
他们现在在整个星球放置了几百根能量柱
They're spreading hundreds of pillars around the globe right now.
几个小时以后
In just a few hours.
他们就会让它们在预定轨道启动
They're going to launch them into orbit.
然后把塞伯坦星球传送到这里来
And bring cybertron into our atmosphere.
那根红色的能量柱可以控制其他的
The red one there, controls the rest.
一旦激活 就会全面启动
He triggers that, it starts the whole thing.
走开 你的任务完成了
Be gone insect operative, your work is done.
遵令
Your Excellency.
你真是个混蛋
You're such a dick.
你想让这一切发生吗?
You want this to happen?
我想活下来 我想多活40年
I want to survive. I want 40 more years.
你以为我愿意吗?
You think I asked for this?
我只是遵从客户意愿
I inherited a client.
对 塞伯坦星球一来 我们都将是奴隶
Yeah, and when Cybertron's here and we're all their slaves
我猜他们还是需要一个人类领导
I guess they'll still need a human leader.
我直说吧 你想活命就得听我的
Get this straight, you want to survive you listen to me.
是时候让地球的奴隶们...
It is time for the slaves of earth...
...见识一下他们的主人了
...to recognize their masters.
封锁城市
Seal off the city.
把狗带出去 把它们关到后面去
Get the dogs out of here now, get them in the back.
我猜他们没告诉过你这部分计划 是吧?
I guess they didn't tell you about this part, did they.
你以为我参加了所有会议吗?
You think I'm at every meeting?
他们答应过我
They promised I'm safe.
他们说我很安全
They said I'm safe.
我们走
Let's roll.
刚才还有信号
Don't have a signal reading.
现在不好使了
It's not working.
撤退
Move back.
外星飞船包围了芝加哥
There's a ring of alien ships around Chicago.
我们的远程轰炸机刚刚被击落
Our high range bombers were just knocked out of the sky.
他们无法突破城中敌人的空中防线
They can't get through enemy air defenses over the city.
我们的卫星被干扰
Our satellites have been jammed.
无法监控敌人的行动
We have no way to monitor the enemies movement.
所有鹰巢部队都撤退了
All NEST teams are on stand down.
目前在空军基地待命
Only have troops at air force base, move out.
距离战斗区只有10分钟的路程
10 minutes from the battle zone.
我们的特种部队正在想办法接近城市
We have special forces trying to gain access to the city.
步兵部队正在试图进入周边区域
An infantry is staging at the perimeter.
等一下 等一下 怎么会这样呢
Excuse me, excuse me, it just doesn't make sense.
我们完全看不到画面吗?
Can't we get any eyes in there at all?
他们一直在击落我们的侦察机
They keep shooting down our drones.
他们要我们看不见
They want us blind.
但我们还有迷你侦察机可以一试
But we do have a couple of mini-drones we're gonna try.
我们可以操纵无人侦察机
Well if we can man these UAV drones,
能不能让它飞往川普大厦吗?
Can we try to redirect them toward, Trump Tower?
那个孩子 威特维奇正在赶往芝加哥的路上
The kid, Witwicky was on his way to Chicago.
霸天虎和它的那个人类间谍
Set some point man human ops there,
就在那栋大厦
before the Decepticons.
听着 我很清楚这一点
Listen, if I know anything, I know this.
这孩子可是霸天虎的死对头
That kid is an alien bad news magnet.
我的天啊
My God.
我们是要在这片混乱中找她吗?
We came here to find her in the middle of all that?
我们真要去吗 埃普斯?
Are we really going out there, Epps?
我不想进去
I'm not going in there.
没有人想进去
No one's going in.
我去
I am.
有没有你们 我都要找到她
With or without you, I'll find her.
你会死的 萨姆
You're gonna get yourself killed, Sam.
那是你想要的吗?
Is that what you want?
你想找死吗?
你一路过来就是为了送死
You came all the way out here to get yourself killed.
是吗? 听着... 听我说
Huh? Listen... to me what I'm saying.
她是因为我才来这儿的 你明白吗?
She's here because of me, do you understand?
听着 你就算进去了
Listen, if you go in this building.
就算她还活着
That's if she's even still alive.
你也没有办法找到她
There's no way you're going to be able to even reach her.
那我应该怎么办?
Well what would you suggest I do.
一切都结束了
It's over.
我很抱歉 但真的结束了
I'm sorry, but it's over.
不
No.
小心 敌机来袭!
Woah, incoming!
我们会把他们杀光
We will kill them all.
清障车 杀了他
Wreckers, kill him.
这会很疼的 非常疼的
This is going to hurt a lot.
你们的领导现在会明白了
Your leaders will now understand.
霸天虎是绝不会放过你们的星球的
Decepticons will never leave your planet alone.
我们要他们相信我们已经离开了
And we needed them to believe we had gone.
今天 以自由的名义
For today, in the name of freedom,
我们向霸天虎开战
we take the battle to them.
我看到你们的飞船被炸了
I saw your ship blow up.
飞船 我们根本就没在里面
The ship, we were never in the ship.
那玩意儿是我们设计出来的
We designed the damn thing, didn't we.
我们躲在第一级火箭推进器里
We were hidden in the first booster rocket to separate,
然后降落在大西洋 跟我们计划的一样
splashed down back in the Atlantic, just as planned.
我们哪都不去
We ain't going no where.
对 没有人能赶走我们
Yeah, no ones exiling us.
汽车人要留在这儿
The Autobots are just staying right here.
我们要帮你们赢得这场战争
We're going to help you win this war.
他们封锁了整座城市 形成了一座堡垒
They're surrounding the city to make a fortress.
这样就没有人能够看到他们的所作所为
So that no one can see what they're up to inside.
我们唯一的机会就是突袭
Our only chance is the element of surprise.
我知道哪里能看到
I think I know where to look.
迷你侦察机正在接近川普大厦
Mini-drones on approach, Trump Tower.
你是说 萨姆正赶往那里吗?
You're telling me, Sam's headed into that?
可怜的孩子
Poor kid.
没准他都无法接近
Probably never got close.
你会驾驶这个 对吧?
Your gonna fly this thing, right?
什么 这手势是什么意思?
What does, what is that, what is that?
马马虎虎
So, so.
好吧 你开得马马虎虎
So you so, so can fly.
这感觉糟透了
That feels terrible.
我们就在你背后
We're right behind you.
好了
All right.
我们进去
We're going in.
城市被封锁了
The city's secure.
人类阻止不了我们
The humans cannot stop us.
太阳落山后
As the afternoon falls,
其余的能量柱都将进入启动位置
the rest of the pillars will reach their launch position.
这就是我多少年前向你保证的胜利
This is the victory I promised you so many years ago
我们要一起重建塞伯坦星球
where we rebuild Cybertron.
一起
together.
我和你合作是为了重建我们的星球
I have gained to work with you that my planet may survive.
我永远不会为你效劳
I will never work for you.
你最好聪明点 分清差别
And you would be wise to remember the difference.
哦 我讨厌这样 我最讨厌等待了
Oh, I'm so sick of this. I'm sick of waiting.
她在哪儿?
Where is she?
她在哪儿?!
Where is she?!
你胆量不小啊
You've got some balls.
不 萨姆!
No, Sam!
不!
No!
卡莉啊!
Carly!
跳
Jump.
大黄蜂 开火
Bee, fire.
大黄蜂 救命
Help him, Bee.
汽车人 他们还活着
Autobots, they're alive.
他们在这儿
They're here, Autobots.
霸天虎 保护能量柱
Decepticons defend the pillar.
升起大桥
Release the bridges.
找到他们
Find them.
萨姆啊
Sam.
你找到我了
You found me.
天涯海角我都要把你找到
I'd find you anywhere.
...快点 快点
...let's go, let's go.
你真是疯了
Well you're crazy.
那是什么 是我们的吗?
What is that, is that us?
是军用的无人侦察机
This thing is a military UAV drone.
检查下还能不能用
Check to see if it's still working.
好的 它还有动力
Yeah, it's still got power.
指控中心 能收到吗?
Flight control, do you copy?
可以旋转吗?
Can you rotate?
能做点什么吗?
Can you do something?
我想我们拍到影像了
I think we got something.
埃普斯 是埃普斯
Epps, we got Epps.
...做点什么
...do something.
拜托 伙计 快点 快点
Come man, work, work.
好的 调高音量
All right, turn the volume up on that.
是他
It's him.
你能旋转吗 换个角度
Can you rotate, something.
太棒了
Yes, yes.
好的 他们看见我们了
Okay, okay they can see us.
芝加哥是坐标原点 明白吗?
Chicago is ground zero, you understand?
- 能听到吗? 明白吗?  - 天哪
- You hear us, understand?  - Jesus.
御天敌在这里...
The Sentinel prime is here...
...他有搭建太空桥需要的组件
...and he has components for his space bridge.
他们在芝加哥河旁的大楼顶上
They're on top of a building on the Chicago river.
他们正在准备运送星球
So they have whole bunch school doing investment
主能量柱能控制一切
The control pillar controls everything.
就在大厦的东南圆顶上
In the southeast cupola.
你们得攻击能量柱 你们必须打下主能量柱
You gotta shoot the pillar. You have to shoot down the pillar.
不然他们会把赛伯坦星球传输到这里 明白吗?
Or they're going to transport Cybertron here,
你确定?
do you understand?
什么?
What?
给我大厦及无人机的位置
Give me the GPS on that building and on that drone.
我们出发
Let's go.
骑士读取坐标
Knights read those co-ordinates.
拉近射程距离
Show the kill chain.
五分钟后在停机坪集合
Guys on the tarmac, five minutes.
- 距此东南方  - 好的
- South east cupalar.  - All right.
我们必须在战斗机发现我们前行动
We need to move before the fighters spot us.
在这里等着 我们去侦察前进路线
Wait here until we scout a route ahead.
我们出发
Let's roll.
救护车 你在高处掩护
Ratchet, cover high.
嘿 你认为那个火箭筒能把主能量柱打下来吗?
Hey, think you could use that rocket to shoot down the pillar?
我们还隔着八条街呢
We're eight blocks away.
近点才能射击
We gotta get closer to take a shot.
不是更接近 要更高
Not closer, higher.
我们需要开阔的视野
We need clear line of sight.
而且它在河的对岸
And it's across the river.
一定要有些时间偷偷爬上去
Gonna have a hell of a time trying to sneaking up.
我们只有一发弹药
We only got one shot.
一发就足够了
One shot's all we need.
我们必须能从地面看到大厦的周围
We gotta be able to see around that building from the ground.
让美国国家安全局把这地区所有摄影机的讯息传给我们
Get NSA to send service specs for any cameras in that area.
也许有些可以用到
Maybe some are working.
红绿灯 提款机 什么都行
Traffic lights, ATM's anything.
听好了
Listen up.
你们想回来吗?
You want to get back?
我们要穿上飞行衣
We're going to have a wing-suit in.
这是接近它的唯一办法
It's the only way to get close.
我不能保证大家都能活着回来
I can't promise anyone a ride home,
但如果你们跟着我的话...
but if you're with me...
这个世界现在需要你
The world needs you now.
我会自己找回家的路 长官
I'll find my own ride home, sir.
还有谁?
Who else?
这里 长官
Right here, sir.
通告塔台 我们...
General warn tower we're...
...采取牵制行动 飞往城市南方
...taking diversionary action to south of the city.
我们正向北行进
We're coming from north and low.
你们丢了一个...
You guys drop in south east...
博派胜利 博派胜利
Autobot victory, Autobot victory.
我得提醒你外面很危险 霸天虎
Gotta warn you. It's scary out there, Decepticons.
他们拿了我的拖车 我需要里面的飞行装备
They got my trailer, I need that flight tech.
震荡波无法同时攻击我们所有人
Shockwave can't hunt all of us at once.
清障车 你们去分散他们的注意力
Wreckers, we need a diversion.
- 我们上吧  - 你们能搞定
- Let's get some.  - You got that right.
听着 我们要到那栋玻璃大厦周围
Listen, we're going to circle around to that glass building.
到一个火箭筒能够射击的高度
We'll get high enough to make the rocket shot.
你们引开他的火力 我们前进
While you guys draw his fire, let's move.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你们不拿着我的城市战斗武器
I'm not going letting you go out there
我不能放你们出去
without my urban-combat prototypes.
我们得走了 齐 快点
We gotta go, Que. Come on.
等等 这可是有用的伟大发明
Wait, they're great inventions for kicking ass.
这些是什么?
What are these?
集束炸弹
Those are boom sticks.
能在30秒内引爆
Armed in thirty seconds.
爪式手套能用来攀爬
Grapple gloves, for climbing.
- 快走 快  - 快点!
- Move out, go on.  - Move!
快走 快走 快走
Go, go, go.
快跑 快跑! 大家快走
Move, move! Let's go.
大家快走 快点
Let's go, come on.
嘿 你要去哪里?
Hey, where you going?
- 不 不 不 停下 停下  - 你去哪里?
- No, no, no. Stop, stop, stop.  - Where you going?
- 别走  - 别把汽车人丢下
- Don't leave.  - Never leave a bro behind.
啊 震荡波来了
Aw, Shockwaves coming.
到楼梯那里去
Go for the stairs.
埃普斯 这边
Epps, this way.
右边受阻 右边受阻
Breaking right, breaking right.
收到 向左转向
Read, rolling left.
又来了一架飞机 从左侧接近
We got another one coming around. Coming on the left side.
我们绕到右侧 绕过去
Going around on to the right side. Going around.
我们用威利斯大楼做掩护
We're going to use Willis Tower for cover.
当我们到达预定高度后
Once we make altitude.
我们就往下跳
We jump.
一号遭到攻击
Hot air. Attack on one now.
- 估计他活不了了  - 求救 求救
- Man I don't think he's going to make it.  - Mayday, mayday.
一号机坠落
Chopper one going down.
快 快 快
Come on, come on, come on.
二十秒钟到达目标
Got them on target, twenty seconds.
我们走 我们走吧
Well here we go, here we go.
跟紧点
Keep it tight.
绕过来
coming around.
好的 锁住 锁住 锁住
All right, focus focus focus
六点钟方向
Six o'clock.
小心 小心!
Watch out, watch out!
哦 该死
Oh, shit.
快出来 让他们出来 让他们出来
Get them out, get them out, get them out.
现在 出来 出来! 跳 跳 快跳
Now, out, out! Jump, jump, jump.
快出去 快出去
Get out, get out.
飞吧 继续
Let's fly, let's move.
让他们全部下去 全部下去
get them all down, get them all down.
救命!
Help!
散开 分开点 分开点
Get separation, track away, track away.
散开 散开
More flap, more flap.
注意六点钟方向 六点钟方向
Check your six, Check your six.
他在我们后面
He's on our ass.
散开
Separate.
正前方有大楼 是死路
Building, dead ahead.
从中间穿过去
Thread the needle.
开伞 开伞!
Pull, pull!
嘿 来吧 我们集结起来
Hey come on we'll line up.
这儿有个家伙还没睡醒
This is a mother getting up here.
快给我过来
Get your fat ass over here.
我来了
I'm coming.
架好火箭筒
Set up the rocket.
来吧
Come on.
我们在上面就位了
We're up and status.
带上集束炸弹
Bring on bomb busters.
20个机器人
20 persons D spot.
那儿 那栋有圆顶的大楼
There, the building with the Prime.
为了我们的兄弟
For our brothers.
不能辜负了他们的牺牲
Let's make this trip worth it.
哦 哦 天啊
Oh, oh God.
哇 这大厦 大厦在晃
Whoa, this building oh the building.
他们在攻击大厦
They're shooting at the building.
这个主意不好
This is not a good idea.
什么?
What?
这不是个好主意 大厦要倒了
This is not a good idea, the building's not stable.
等一下 如果我们不去做自己能做的事
Just stop for a second. We don't do what we can do.
那么好吧 我们都得死了
Then it doesn't matter, we all die.
对吗? 是你表现的时候了 来吧
Right? It's your time, come on man.
我快要崩溃了
I'm incapable of collapse.
反正我原来就有心脏病
I'm having a heart attack anyway.
大厦要倒了
The building is going over.
- 坚持住  - 找掩护
- Hang on.  - Take cover.
没关系 停住了
It's okay, it's done.
伙计们 快看
Guys, look.
敌袭 敌袭
Incoming, incoming.
大家躲起来
Everybody hide.
不要...
Don't...
...乱动
...move.
火力掩护
Cover fire.
射击玻璃窗 跳出窗外
Shoot the glass, jump out the window.
跳
Jump.
萨姆 我停不下来
Sam, I can't stop.
射击玻璃窗
Shoot the glass.
萨姆啊
Sam.
大家还好吗?
Is everyone okay?
你还好吗?
You okay?
这是什么鬼东西?
What the hell was that?
这怪物正盯着我看
This Zevo thing is looking at me.
什么?
What?
甚至有个会震荡的霸天虎跟着他
He's even got a undulating decepticon with it.
快回来
Get back.
它来了 楼梯被堵住了
It's coming up, the stairs are blocked.
嘿 我们怎么离开这里
Hey, how do we get out of here.
嘿 来吧
Hey, come on.
主啊 只要让我离开这里继续活着
Oh lord, just let me get out of this alive.
我把养老金通通给你
I'll give you annuities, and get it together.
我们得快逃
Move, we gotta move.
为什么霸天虎总是有最好的配备
Why do the Decepticons always get the good shit.
快走
Move.
我们得快离开 伙计们
We got leave people.
把你的手给我
Give me your hand.
拉住她
You know, got her.
把她丢到防火通道去
Let's drop her to the fire escape.
萨姆啊!
Sam!
哇 我们得快走
Whoa, we gotta move.
趴下 快走
Get down, move.
我来救你了
I'm coming for you.
擎天柱!
Optimus!
清障车
Wreckers.
我们来了
We're coming.
在世界各地的霸天虎们
Decepticons around the world.
启动能量柱
Launch the pillars.
诶 我们太失败了
Ahh, we are so lost.
总是被忽略
Always left out.
太好了
Excellent.
该是我们发号施令了
It's time to lay down the law.
现在就搞点破坏
By to be the hurt now.
他们开始了
They're starting.
你看
You see it.
下来了
Get down.
萨姆和卡莉在哪里?
Where is Sam and Carly?
我们可以从这里走
We can run this way.
我就让你做一件事
I give you one thing to do.
就这一件事 你都干不好
One thing to do and you drop the ball on that.
这也不是我负责的
I never signed for all of this.
外星人攻击我 跑来跑去追我
Got aliens blasting me, running around chasing me.
我躲在教堂和...
I'm ducking in churches and...
...大厦还有这些废墟
...buildings and all that kind of crap, maybe.
这简直是胡搞 我没有要求加入 埃普斯
This is bullshit, I didn't sign up for this, Epps.
我在尝试冷静下来
I'm trying to keep it down.
聊聊吧 就你和我
What a treat, you and me. Alone.
快 快 快跑
Come on, come on. Let's run.
好吧 他追的是我而不是你
Okay, he's after me not you.
快跑 跑
Wait run, run.
你躲不了的 小子
You can't hide, boy.
跑 快走
Run, move it.
我太喜欢你那小脚
Love it when your little insect feet,
...试图逃跑的样子!
...try to run!
你!
You!
还以为你会站在我们这边 小子
Thought you were working for us, boy.
萨姆啊!
Sam!
我的眼睛
My eye.
我的眼睛!
My eye!
目标 霸天虎
Target, Decepticon.
萨姆啊!
Sam!
雷尼克斯 你得救救萨姆
Lennox you've got to save, Sam.
- 你一定要救他  - 他在做什么?
- You've got to save him.  - What is he doing?
这个最好能用
This better work.
噢 我看不见了 看不见了
Ow, ow, ow. I can't see, I can't see.
萨姆 抓住我的手
Sam,take my hand.
把线剪断 把线剪断 不是那样
Cut the line, cut the line. Not that much.
- 我在试  - 快剪线
- I'm trying.  - The line.
你们这些人类
You humans.
炸弹还有20秒就要爆炸了
20 seconds for that bomb.
什么炸弹?
What bomb?
就那边那个炸弹
See that boom.
我拿到了
I got it.
现在抓住我
Well hold onto to me now.
我要给你一脚
I'll kick you.
好吧 他死了
Well he's dead.
他会去找其余汽车人...
Okay, he's going to run with...
...我们在河边汇合
...the rest of the Autobots, meet us at the river.
好的
All right.
他把我吸进来的 我也没办法
He sucked me in, there was nothing I could do.
好吧 这是一个丛集排列
Uh oh. This is a total cluster form.
我们必须过河
We gotta get across the river.
你看到了吗?
You see that?
她说主能量柱就在第一个圆顶里
She said the control pillar is in that first cupola.
走 快走
Go, move. Let's move.
战斧导弹就绪
Tomahawks are inbound.
预计到达时间二十分钟
ETA, twenty minutes.
我进入了交通监控仪
I'm in the traffic cameras.
四个汽车人被捉
Four Aubobots are captured.
哦 天哪 我们孤立无援了
Oh my God, we're helpless.
一切都已设定好 能量柱...
It was set to happen. With those...
...闪得越快 说明传输很快就会开始
...pulses getting faster it was going to happen soon.
没有发现擎天柱
No sign of Optimus.
我们怎样才能将这些桥放下来?
How do we get these bridges down?
散开 去那里看看
Spread out, check in there.
埃普斯 原来你在这里 你在干什么?
Epps, you're here, what are you doing?
时间不多了
Time is wack.
更糟的是
Even worse,
我们无法穿过河去那栋楼
we can't get across the river to that dude.
楼上的汽车人都被包围了
And the Aubobots are upstairs surrounded.
注意转动监控仪镜头 好吧
Just pan the camera around, all right.
好的 好 向右转动 是你负责的
All right pan, pan right, that's you.
派一个小队去大桥的控制室
Trying to get to that bridge control.
他们在那里干什么? 他们只是干站着
What are they doing there? They are just standing there.
等一下 小荷
Hang on, Dutch.
你试试能不能控制那座桥
See if you can hack into the bridge.
长官 海豹突击队到了
Sir, the seals are here.
真是太好了 伙计们 你们有什么武器?
Oh it's a good day boys, what do you got?
一共有十个人 长官
Got ten manned navy seal element sir,
要为战斧导弹标明目标
and just charging in Tomahawks.
- 还要多久?  - 15分钟
- How long?  - Fifteen.
别紧张
Take it easy.
放开我
Get off me.
好吧 我们需要...
All right, you're gonna need your...
...40毫米的榴弹发射器
...40 mike-mikes in your frags.
进入全自动模式
Go for auto,
震荡波会破坏他们的电路
the vibrations jack up their circuits.
狙击手 瞄准眼睛射击
Snipers, shoot for the eyes.
好了 现在你们的目标就在那座大楼的楼顶
All right your target is up on top of that building.
瞄准圆形屋顶
That cupola.
你们真是可悲啊 汽车人
How doomed you are, Autobots.
你们永远也不会明白
You simply fail to understand.
集体的利益
That the needs of the many,
大于个人的利益
out weigh the needs of the few.
激活太空桥
Activating the bridge.
他们在高兴什么呢
They have to guard something.
我们在他们飞船的操作中心
We're in the heart of their ship.
我们来开一会儿吧
Let's give him a little ride.
呵呵 我们要毁了这条船
Ho, ho we going to screw this ship up.
是128K二进制代码
It's 128K binary inscription code.
很难破解
It's difficult.
但我会破解的 马上破解
But not for me, I'm in.
桥 放下
Bridge, down.
桥放下来了
The bridge is coming down.
有人在帮助我们
Someone's watching over us.
真开心能与你合作 西摩
Pleasure working with you, Seymour.
我相信你肯定会这么说
I believe you're suppose to say.
干得漂亮 小荷
Good job, Dutch.
谢谢夸奖
Danke schoen.
擎天柱 他们激活了能量柱
Prime, they're triggering the pillars.
阶下囚 你们还要留下阶下囚吗?
Prisoners, you're keeping prisoners?
是的
Yeeesss.
你应该教教他们什么是尊重
You need to teach them about respect.
原来只是笔交易
This was all business,
但现在是私人恩怨 你明白我的意思吗?
but now it's personal. Do you understand me?
我明白
I understand.
没有阶下囚
No prisoners.
只有战利品
Only trophies.
大黄蜂 我觉得他们会把我们都杀了
B, I think they're going to kill us.
你
You.
你的时辰到了
You're time is up.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait.
我们投降
We surrender.
我们给...
We give...
...快点走
...Move it.
难道我们就不能谈谈吗?
Can't we talk this out?
我们可都是讲理的人
We're all a bunch of good chaps.
我是说 总的来说... 啊!!!
I mean in all... unh!!!
为什么你...
Why did you...
再见了 老朋友
Goodbye my old friend.
现在你是我的了
You're mine now.
我要帮他
Gotta help him.
什么?
What?
你要干什么?
What are you doing?
我要去帮他
I gotta help him.
你帮不了他
You can't help him.
萨姆啊
Sam.
转过去
Turn around.
我们 我们决不怕死
We, we never had it around.
我们做到了 大脑 我们做到了
We did it Brains. We did it.
把这艘飞船斯成碎片
Rip this ship apart.
- 我们... 我们干得可真漂亮 就我和你  - 没错
- We... we had a nice run Brains, you and me.  - Yeah.
我们会死的
We're gonna die.
好了 伙计们 跟我们走
Okay baby, you are coming with us.
我们走 你们...
Let's go, you guys...
...跟着陆战队 快去
...follow that ground team, go.
快 快 快
Move, move, move.
这里是3楼 我们要爬到45楼
Third floor, load up a 45.
你们两个狙击手 来这里
All right you two snipers right here.
好了 做好准备
All right, dock up.
20分钟后跳伞
Its up to twenty minutes.
在这里准备好射击
Set the shot right here.
好了 做好准备
All right, set up.
他们在楼下
Downstairs.
目标有5个 震荡波就在我们正下方
We got five targets and Shockwave right below us.
大家一起跳
Everybody jump.
好了 快点 做好准备 做好准备
All right, let's go. Get ready, get ready.
跳 跳
Go, go.
狙击手 瞄准眼睛射击
Snipers, take out their eyes.
好了 爆破组 准备安置炸弹
All right, Demo team lets crank steel.
引爆
Turning steel.
等我口令开火
Don't fire until I tell you.
快来帮忙!
Go!
好了 干得漂亮
All right, good job.
- 是啊  - 开火!
- Yes.  - Fire!
我们打中他了
We got him.
是啊
Yeah.
他想逃跑
On the run.
汽车人 攻击
Autobots, attack.
朝那座桥开炮
Mortar that bridge.
现在 世界是我们的了
It's our world, now.
开始传输
Commence transport.
天啊
My God.
擎天柱!
Optimus!
你去死吧
You die.
不
Nooo.
有本事下来 御天敌
Get down here, Sentinel.
擎天柱
Optimus.
那我就来好好教训你
You forget your place.
我给你带来了塞伯坦星球
I bring you Cybertron.
你的家
Your home.
但你仍然选择了人类
And still you choose humanity.
是你教导我 自由是每个人的权利
You were the one who taught me freedom is everyone's right.
我会再次触发能量柱
I will retrigger that pillar.
那你就要先过我这一关
Then you'll have to go through me.
好 我去帮你
Okay, I got to help.
- 不 别去  - 现在听我说
- No, you don't.  - Listen to me now.
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine.
- 你答应过的  - 你会没事的 我保证
- You promised.  - You're going to be fine.
我要去能量柱那边
I gotta get to that pillar.
保护能量柱
Guards to the pillar.
我们去帮汽车人
We got Autobots.
快走 快走!
Move, move!
快来支援我
Reinforcements to me.
霸天虎6号 朝擎天柱开火
Decepticon six, fire at Optimus.
开火 开始发射战斧导弹
Fire, I need those tomahawks here now.
第一波 发射
First wave, incoming.
我们要掩护擎天柱
We gotta cover for, Optimus.
霸天虎
Decepticons,
把能量柱给我拿来
trigger the pillar.
重启能量柱
Restart that pillar.
触发能量柱
Trigger the pillars.
我快撑不下去了
I can't hold him.
这一步我必须要迈出去
This step I must bend.
不
No.
伊万 10秒后命中！危险！
Evan, ten seconds Tomahawks close.
利维四号 重复 重复 14250
Fourth levi, echo echo 1 4 2 5 zero,
- 发现表面接触  - 查询身份
- Found surface contact.  - Got an ID.
捕获目标
Target acquired.
迪兰啊!
Dylan!
- 对  - 不!
- Right.  - No!
- 该死  - 迪兰
- Shit.  - Dylan.
住手 住手
Stop, stop.
不
No.
你不能这么做
You can't do this.
知道吗
Okay.
对我来说 未来只有一个
There's only one future for me.
塞伯坦星球
Cybertron.
你得救了
You are saved.
终于得救了
At last.
哦 你是来投降的吗?
Oh, have you come to surrender?
- 这一切都值得吗?  - 当然值得
- Was it all worth it?  - Obviously.
你费尽周折 只是为了将御天敌救活
All your work to bring Sentinel back.
但显然 现在一切都由他说了算
And now clearly he has all the power.
这一切是多么的可笑啊
It's actually almost tragic.
你竟敢教训我 奴隶
You dare lecture me, slave.
你们霸天虎最终征服了这个星球
Your decepticons finally conquering this planet.
但他们的领导却不是你
And yet their leader wasn't you.
会是我的 永远都是我
It will be me, it will always be me.
就现在
Any minute from now.
他们都会开始取笑你
They'll be laughing.
你就是御天敌的奴才
You're Sentinels bitch.
再射击!
Again!
你选择你的立场
You chose sides.
但选错了
You chose wrong.
一直以来 你都是最勇猛的
Always the bravest of us.
但你在重要决定面前 却左右为难
But you could never make the hard decisions.
现在!
Now!
我们的星球会幸存下去
Our planet will survive.
不
No.
曾几何时 我们是上帝
We were Gods once.
我们所有人
All of us.
但在这里
But here,
求你了
Please.
他们只能听我的命令
They'll only be one.
这是我的星球
This is MY planet.
我刚刚拯救了另一个世界
I just saved a whole other world.
你觉得你是个英雄吗?
You think you're a hero?
嗯 是你觉得自己是个英雄吧
Huh, you think you're a hero.
不
No.
我只是个信使
I'm just a messenger.
传输没有中断
It's still connected.
看着 等等
Watch, wait up.
- 大黄蜂!  - 快走 快走 快点吧
- B!  - Get going, get going. Let's move it.
哦 传输没有中断
Oh it's still connected.
我们一起瞄准它开火
Lets lock it that.
不
No.
我们休战吧
We need a truce.
我只不过是想控制所有人
All I wanted was to be back in charge.
而且...
Besides...
没有我 你又能怎样呢?
Who would you be without me?
擎天柱
Prime.
那就来试试吧
Time to find out.
擎天柱 我只不过是想
Optimus. All I ever wanted,
让我们的种族得以生存
was the survival of our race.
现在你明白 我背叛你的原因了吧
You must see why I had to betray you.
你没有背叛我
You didn't betray me.
你背叛了你自己
You betrayed yourself.
不 擎天柱!
No, Optimus!
萨姆啊
Sam.
我爱你
I love you.
在这个世界上 我只要你
You're the only thing I need in this world.
我答应你 只要能补偿你 我什么都愿意做
And I'll do anything to make it up to you, I promise.
那就兑现你的诺言吧
I'm gonna hold you to that.
永远都不要放手
Just never let me go.
我答应你
Promise.
是戒指啊
Rings.
我爱死这辆车了
I love this car.
话别说那么早
But, you gotta slow down.
你也不要这么心急 好吧
You gotta slow way down. Okay.
我只是帮你一把而已
I'm just trying to help out.
不管任何战争
In any war.
结束后都有片刻安宁
There are calms, between storms.
- 你们很勇猛  - 也许某天 我们会失去信仰
- You fought bravely.  - There will be days when we loose faith.
也许某天 朋友会背叛我们
Days when our allies turn against us.
但我们放弃这座星球
But the day will never come.
以及它的子民的这一天
That we forsake this planet.
永远不会来临
And it's people.
这就是我所说的美好未来的开始
That's what I called such a beautiful future
逮捕他
Arrest him
- 这根本不值得  - 把他带走
- It's worthy it  - Get him out of here
我就想进"监狱" 夏洛特 我不在乎
I just got her for the love. I don't care.
把我关进去吧
I want going. Take me in. I want going. Let's going